what's your thoughts on milk it's
你对牛奶有什么看法？
problematic current Dairy is not
目前乳制品存在
something we should consume so you might
问题，我们不应该食用。你可能
not know this
不知道这一点，
but that's crazy Dr Mark Hyman one of
但这太疯狂了。马克·海曼博士是
the world leading doctors in functional
世界领先的功能
medicine and an expert in helping people
医学医生之一，也是帮助人们
understand how they can live their
了解如何
longest healthiest life what are your
健康长寿的专家。你
thoughts on his imp so we have a massive
对他的观点有什么看法？我们面临着严重的
obesity problem and we don't have any
肥胖问题，而且没有任何
good Solutions so something comes along
有效的解决方案。所以，当某种减肥产品出现时，它
that makes you lose weight that's a huge
极具
attractive thing but the side effect
吸引力，但其副作用却很
Prof file in this is scary people are
可怕。人们并
not aware that and by the way they're
没有意识到这一点。顺便说一句，他们甚至
thinking of giving it to 5-year-old kids
考虑给5岁的孩子服用，这简直太可怕了。
which is just terrifying but we live in
我们生活在
a toxic landscape of enticing addictive
一个充满诱人上瘾的
highly processed food which is why 93%
高加工食品的有毒环境中，这就是为什么93%的
of us have some metabolic dysfunction we
人都有某种代谢功能障碍。我们
know that causes mental health issues
知道这会导致心理健康问题，例如抑郁、焦虑、注意力缺陷障碍（ADD）和
depression anxiety add gun violence it
枪支暴力（
kills 11 million people a year but these
每年造成1100万人死亡）。但这些
are not inevitable problems so for
问题并非不可避免。
example I had a kid with ADD who was so
例如，我有一个患有注意力缺陷障碍（ADD）的孩子，他
handwriting at 12 years old but after 2
12岁时的症状非常严重，以至于你根本看不懂他的字迹。但两个月后，
months he went from having severe ADD
他的ADD
symptoms to excelling and score and
症状就得到了改善，并且表现出色。 得分，
there's so many things that you can do
你可以做很多事情，
but people have to understand that you
但人们必须明白，你
cannot use willpower to control your
不能仅凭意志力控制你的
food Behavior it's a problem of
饮食行为，这是一个
education for example if you eat sugar
教育问题。例如，如果你早上吃含糖的麦片、
in the Morning cereal pancakes Bagels
煎饼或百吉饼，
it's the worst possible thing we can do
这是最糟糕的事情。
string training three times a week 20
每周三次，每次20分钟的绳索训练
minutes is really key for longevity and
对于长寿至关重要，
this is really important we call it the
这一点非常重要。我们称之为“
five FS for getting healthy but most of
健康五要素”（Five FS），但
us do the opposite so
我们大多数人却恰恰相反。所以，
it's congratulations Dario gang we we've
恭喜Dario团队，我们
made some progress 63% of you that
取得了一些进展。63%的
listen to this podcast regularly don't
定期收听我们播客的听众没有
subscribe which is down from
订阅，比之前的
69% our goal is 50% so if you've ever
69%有所下降，我们的目标是50%。所以，如果你
liked any of the videos we've posted if
喜欢我们发布的任何视频，或者
you like this channel can you do me a
喜欢这个频道，请帮我一个
quick favor and hit the Subscribe button
小忙，点击订阅按钮。
it helps this channel more than you know
这对频道的帮助远超你的想象，而且
and the bigger the channel gets as
正如
you've seen the bigger the guests get
你所看到的，频道越壮大，邀请的嘉宾也就越多。
thank you and enjoy this
谢谢，祝你享受这期
[Music]
[音乐]
episode
节目。Mark，
Mark if someone's just on this
如果有人刚收听这个播客，
podcast can you tell me why they should
你能告诉我他们为什么应该
stay and
留下来继续
listen great question great question the
收听吗？问得好，
answer is quite simple you're going to
答案很简单。 你将有机会窥见
of your
你自身
health and the future of medicine itself
健康的未来，以及医学本身的未来，
and the way to think about things the
还有你思考健康的方式——
you think about symptoms you have or
你如何看待自己或家人的症状或疾病，你如何思考如何
have the way you think about optimiz her
优化健康。
health you're going to have a window
你将有机会了解
into what the next generation of
下一代对健康的
thinking is about this a paradigm shift
思考方式，这是一种范式转变，
that's akin to Columbus saying the Earth
类似于哥伦布说地球
is not flat or Galileo saying the the
不是平的，或者伽利略说
the the the Earth is not uh is not the
地球不是
center of the universe you know these
宇宙的中心。你知道，这些都是
are massive scientific Paradigm or
巨大的科学范式，或者达尔文的
evolutionary theory by Darwin think
进化论。
about physics at the turn of the last
想想上世纪之交的物理学，以及
with Einstein's discoveries of
爱因斯坦发现
Relativity we are now at that stage in
相对论后发生的巨大变化。我们现在正处于生物学发展的一个阶段，在
the first time in history of science and
科学和医学史上，我们第一次理解了
medicine the natural laws of biology and
生物学的自然规律以及
how the Body Works what is functional
人体的运作方式。什么是功能
medicine how do you like I've heard the
医学？你觉得怎么样？我
word before but I've never really
以前听说过这个词，但我从未真正
understood the true definition yeah I
理解它的真正定义。说实话，
mean I don't particularly like the word
我不太喜欢这个词。
to be honest with you Stephen I think I
斯蒂芬，我觉得功能医学
implications for people but essentially
对很多人来说可能有点让人困惑，但本质上，
the way I would describe it as a new way
我会把它描述为一种
of thinking about solving the puzzle of
解决慢性病难题的新思路，
chronic disease looking at root causes
着眼于根本原因，将
seeing the body as a system as a network
人体视为一个系统、一个网络。
it's the medicine of why not what not
它关注的不是
what disease do you have but why do you
你得了什么病，而是你为什么会
have it it's a science of creating
得这种病。它是一门创造
Health how do we create Health what are
健康的科学，探讨如何创造健康、哪些因素会
the things that are impediments to
阻碍健康、如何
health how do we get rid of those and
消除这些因素、以及
what are the ingredients for health and
健康的要素是什么、
how do we provide those and it's not
如何提供这些要素。其实健康的要素并不多，
that big a list like we're biological
毕竟我们都是
organisms right and so functional
生物体。功能
medicine is a systematic way of thinking
医学是一种系统的思维方式，
it's an operating system or
它就像一个操作系统或
methodology uh heuristic let's say to to
方法论，或者说是一种启发式方法，用来
unpack all of your body ology and all
剖析你身体的所有机能和所有
the inputs we call the exposome and make
我们称之为“暴露组”的输入，从而
sense of what your personal story is and
理解你的个人经历，并制定
and personalized and approach to
个性化的
diagnosis and treatment so you know we
诊断和治疗方法。你知道，
always say in functional medicine you
在功能医学中，我们总是说，
can have one cause that creates many
一个病因可能导致多种
diseases or one disease it can have many
疾病，或者一种疾病可能由多种
causes so for example gluten can cause
因素引起。例如，麸质可能导致
everything from osteoporosis to autism
从骨质疏松症到自闭症
to schizophrenia to R arthritis to
等各种疾病。 从精神分裂症到关节炎，再到
anemia
贫血、
to hair loss alpia I mean it can cause a
脱发，我的意思是，它可以引发
million things and it's one inciting
无数的事情，而这可能只是一个诱发
event or you can have you know one
事件。或者，你可能患有一种
disease like depression that can be
疾病，比如抑郁症，而抑郁症的病因有
caused by many things depression is a
很多。抑郁症是一种
symptom right it's not a proac
症状，对吧？它不是营养
deficiency right it's caused by many
缺乏症，对吧？它是由多种
factors it could be that you had a major
因素引起的。可能是你经历过重大
trauma or or a loss it could be that
创伤或失去亲人；可能是
you're vitamin D deficient it could be
你缺乏维生素D；可能是
that you're eating gluten it creates
你摄入了麸质，这会导致
inflammation in your brain it could be
大脑炎症；可能是
that you're not taking acid blocker for
你多年来没有服用抑酸剂治疗
years for reflux because you're have the
反流，因为你的
wrong diet and that causes be2
饮食不健康，这会导致β2
deficiency that causes depression or it
缺乏，从而引发抑郁症；也
could be because you're eating a lot lot
可能是因为你吃了很多
of sushi and that has mercury that
寿司，而寿司中含有汞，这会
causes depression or maybe it's because
导致抑郁症；或者可能是因为
you hate sushi and fish and you don't
你讨厌寿司和鱼，所以你不
eat any fish and you have omega-3
吃鱼，导致你缺乏ω-3
deficiency or you maybe have in some
脂肪酸；或者你可能患有某种
resistance and diabetes that can cause
抵抗力低下和糖尿病，这些都会导致
depression and inflammation in the brain
抑郁症和大脑炎症。
so depression is just a name we give to
所以，抑郁症只是我们用来描述
people who share a collection of
一系列共同
symptoms most of the diseases we have
症状的人群的一个名称。 我们现在所说的
that we describe as obesity or diabetes
肥胖、糖尿病、
or heart disease or cancer they're not
心脏病或癌症等疾病，其实并不能
really helpful to understand the true
帮助我们理解真正的
root cause they're just describing the
根本原因，它们只是在描述
symptoms it's descriptive right and so
症状，是描述性的。
functional medicine is a really
功能医学则是一种
different model model uh it's also could
截然不同的模式，也可以
be called Network medicine with the
称为网络医学。
there's a textbook out of Harvard by
哈佛大学的拉拉西（Larasi）写了一本教科书，
larasi that talks about the network
探讨了网络
biology we have you know how we need to
生物学。我们需要
think about multia factorial causes of
思考疾病的多因素成因，
disease there's many factors there not
其中涉及许多因素，而不仅仅是
just one and then multimodal
一个。此外，我们也需要多模式干预，而不仅仅是
interventions not just one we're looking
单一疗法。我们永远
never going to find it you know but a
不可能找到治疗阿尔茨海默病的“灵丹妙药”。但一项
study that looked at multiple
研究考察了
interventions of diet and lifestyle and
饮食、生活方式、
exercise and aggressive treatment of
运动以及积极治疗
risk factors showed a regression of
风险因素等多种干预措施，结果显示
Alzheimer's not one drug but many many
阿尔茨海默病有所缓解。这并非单一药物的作用，而是多种
different modalities that optimize
不同疗法共同作用的结果，从而优化了
health so it's really to me the most
健康状况。因此，对我来说，这真的是
exciting time in medicine it's this this
医学领域最激动人心的时刻。这种
Paradigm sh is happening it's happening
范式正在发生，
fast and it's being accelerated through
而且发展迅速，这得益于
this sort of Advent of our our ability
我们
to do deep phenomic di Diagnostics so
进行深度表型组学诊断的能力的提升。
phenomics is essentially the expression
表型组学本质上是
of your biology any moment your genome
你生物学在任何时刻的表达。你的基因组
is fixed right but your phenome is
是固定的，对吧？但你的表型组
essentially the the things that your
本质上是你的
body expresses whether it's health or
身体所表达的一切，无论是健康还是
disease was there any personal
疾病。有没有什么个人
experiences that made you more drawn
经历让你更倾向于将
towards focusing your life on health and
生命重心放在健康和
helping people absolutely I mean I I've
帮助他人上？当然有。我的意思是，我一直对此很
always been interested so I don't know
感兴趣，所以我也不知道为什么。
why I think it was I visited my sister
我想可能是因为我去阿默学院看望我姐姐，
at ammer college and went to the veggie
去了素食
room and had whole grain bread and
餐厅，吃了全麦面包、
peanut butter and honey I'm like this is
花生酱和蜂蜜。我觉得这很好吃，因为我
good I'm vegetarian so I just sort of
是素食主义者。所以我就慢慢
got into it and then I studied Buddhism
喜欢上了素食，然后我又学习了佛教，也开始接触佛教。
and got into that so I I think I all
我想这些都潜移默化地影响
that was sort of seated in me and then I
着我。后来我又
started n studies in yoga which is sort
开始学习瑜伽，瑜伽是一门
of a science of really healing the mind
真正疗愈心灵的科学，而
and Buddhism is healing the mind so
佛教也是疗愈心灵的，所以我
always sort of got into that uh but
一直都对这方面很感兴趣。但是，在我
went to work at this place called Kya
去一家叫Kya
Ranch it's a health
Ranch的疗养
resort and I got very ill I had lived in
胜地工作之后，发生了一件事。我病得很重。我之前住在
China and basically was breathing in
中国，冬天
Mercury Laden air uh in Beijing in the
在北京呼吸着含汞的空气，
winter and I had an air filter I would
我当时用的是空气净化器。 我
clean it every day and that air filter
每天都清理空气过滤器，但里面
was full of mercury CU it's in the S
全是汞。汞存在于煤炭里，存在于
it's in the coal that they burn they
他们燃烧的煤炭里。他们
burn raw coal in the city and I haed it
在城里烧的是原煤，我
every day and when I got back from China
每天都吸入这些汞。当我从中国回来后，
um there was something that happened I
发生了一些事。我
got some gut infection and my system
得了肠胃感染，我的身体机能
just collapsed one day I was riding my
突然崩溃。有一天，我还能
bike 100 miles a day the next day I
每天骑自行车100英里，第二天就连
couldn't walk up the stairs one day I
楼梯都爬不上去了。有一天，我同时要照顾
had 30 patients and I could remember
30个病人，不用做笔记就能记住
everybody's name and story and
每个人的名字、病史等等，而且
everything at the end of the day with no
一天结束时还能毫无
problem to not being able to remember
障碍地口述所有内容。但有时，
where I was at the end of a sentence
我却连一句话说到哪里都记不住。我甚至
from where I started and I couldn't read
无法
a book to my kids out loud and actually
大声朗读给孩子们听，因为我根本听不懂。
understand it I could either read it and
我只能勉强读懂，或者大声朗读，但自己却完全
out loud and not know what I was saying
不知道在说什么。
my brain just stopped working my immune
我的大脑停止了运转，免疫
system not working my gut stopped
系统停止了运作，肠道也停止了
working my whole body just collapsed I
运作，整个身体都垮了。我
developed chronic fatigue syndrome and I
患上了慢性疲劳综合征，
felt like I was walking through mud and
感觉就像在泥潭里行走。我花了数
it took me years to figure it out uh
年时间才弄明白是怎么回事，真的花了数
really years and I got introduced to
年。后来，我接触到了
functional medicine at that time I heard
功能医学。 当时我听说这件事，
about I said this either is lunacy or
心想这要么是疯话，要么
it's genius and if it's true I devoted
是天才之举。如果是真的，我就全身心投入，想
to finding out whether it's true for me
弄明白它是否真的适用于
for my own healing and for my patients
我自身，也适用于我的病人。
because if it if it was true everything
因为如果是真的，一切都会不
was going to be different it's like you
一样，就像
know like discovering the Earth wasn't
发现地球不是
flat well if that's true then everything
平的一样。如果这是真的，那一切都会不
is different and so I dove into it head
一样。所以我一头扎进去，努力
first to heal myself and then I started
治愈自己。然后我开始
using my patience and that that feeling
运用我的耐心，那种
of being sick drove me because I was I
病痛的感觉驱使着我，因为我很
was clear that I wasn't crazy chronic
清楚自己没有疯。慢性
fatigue syndrome was thought to be a you
疲劳综合征以前被认为是一种
know sort of a psychological disease and
心理疾病，但
now the data is really clear the NH just
现在数据非常清晰。英国国家健康研究所（NH）
came out with a large paper I think last
上周发表了一篇长文，
week talking about the biomarkers and
讨论了生物标志物、
the biology and the mology and the
生物学、分子学、
mitochondrial dysfunction and the
线粒体功能障碍、
inflammation and all the things that do
炎症以及所有可能
go wrong and I I knew was I wasn't crazy
出错的因素。我知道我没有疯，
and I knew I wasn't mentally ill and I
我知道我没有精神疾病，我
knew I wasn't depressed and I knew I
知道我没有抑郁症，我知道我没有注意力缺陷障碍，
didn't have ADD and you know I knew I
我知道我
wasn't getting dementia at 36 years old
不会患上痴呆症。 我36岁了，
and so I I I I really had to understand
所以我必须
my biology internally on a cellular
从细胞层面了解我自身的生物学，
level and reverse engineer my way back
并逆向工程，找到恢复
to health and so that forced me just out
健康的方法。这迫使我出于
of survival to to dig deep into the
生存本能，深入研究正在
science of what was happening and then
发生的事情背后的科学原理，然后从根源上解决问题，并
to attack that and then start to use it
开始将其应用于
on my patients and when I would to use
我的病人身上。当我将这些方法应用于
it on my patients I was shocked I would
我的病人时，我感到非常震惊。比如，有些
have someone coming with autoimmune
病人患有自身免疫性
disease they had for years and I say do
疾病多年，我根据这些
principles and they would get better or
原理告诉他们这样做、那样做，他们的病情就好转了。或者，有些病人患有偏头痛
years and I would check and they would
年，我检查后发现他们对
have a food sensitivity to eggs they
鸡蛋过敏，他们的偏头痛就
stop and go away or I would take someone
停止了，消失了。还有一些糖尿病患者，我通过“
right approach with food is medicine and
食疗”的正确方法治疗，他们的糖尿病也
the diabetes would go away so I would
消失了。我
started seeing all these what I thought
开始看到所有这些我认为
were Miracles or things that wouldn't
是奇迹的事情，或者说是那些看似不可能
change or treating kids with autism or
改变的事情。比如，我治疗患有自闭症或注意力缺陷障碍（ADD）的儿童，
add or and we can we can share in the
我们可以在
show notes but I had a kid with ADD who
节目笔记中分享，但我有一个患有ADD的孩子，
handwriting at 12 years old and after
12岁时他的字迹非常潦草，根本无法辨认，
two months he went from having severe
两个月后，他的病情得到了显著改善。 他之前患有严重的注意力缺陷
ADD symptoms and all these other health
障碍症状和其他各种健康
issues and I fixed his gut I optimized
问题，我帮他调理了肠道，优化了
his nutrition I I get the lead out of
他的营养，排出了
his system I got all the processed food
他体内的铅，让他
out and he went from being completely
戒掉了所有加工食品。两个月后，他从几乎完全
non barely non-functioning to excelling
丧失功能，
in school to having perfect Penman ship
到在学校成绩优异，书法完美。
after two months and I'm like wow this
我当时就觉得，哇，这太
is crazy if you just look at the image
不可思议了！看看
of this and can share it on the show
这张照片，如果你愿意，可以分享到节目
notes if you want it was like okay
笔记里。我当时就想，这里面肯定有
something is going on here that that we
什么我们
don't completely understand and if it's
尚未完全理解的奥秘。如果仅仅是
something as simple as optimizing his
优化他的
gut and optimizing his nutrition and
肠道、优化他的营养、
getting rid of the the toxin in his body
清除体内毒素就能让
and the Brain could function again then
大脑恢复功能，那么
so many people who are suffering don't
很多正在遭受痛苦的人就不必再
need to suffer and that's really what
受苦了。这才是真正
drove me was just seeing so many people
激励我的动力：看到那么多人遭受
suffering without need and how easy it
不必要的痛苦，而
was to fix them once you understood
一旦理解了，治愈他们其实如此简单。
right we're at that stage in medicine
我们现在的医学发展到了一个阶段，
where the answers are here the science
答案就在这里，科学
and technology is here it's just not
和技术都已具备，只是还没有得到
applied and so my whole life has been
应用。因此，我毕生的
driven by The Passion of trying to
热情都源于帮助
relieve needless suffering for millions
数百万人摆脱不必要的痛苦，
of people these chronic diseases that
这些慢性疾病
are now accounting for you know almost
如今已占据了人们生活的很大一部分。 你知道，
$1 in5 dollar of our entire economy that
我们整个经济中几乎五分之一的资金都花在了这些上，导致
are bankrupting America and I think the
美国破产。我认为
NHS is not far behind us in the UK you
英国的国民医疗服务体系（NHS）也紧随其后。你
know we're we're these are not
知道，这些
inevitable problems you know heart
问题并非不可避免。
disease diabetes many cancers dementia
心脏病、糖尿病、多种癌症、痴呆症、
autoimmune diseases these are just
自身免疫性疾病，这些疾病
exploding in the last 100 years they
在过去一百年里呈爆炸式增长。它们
weren't around before it wasn't because
以前并不存在，
we didn't live long it wasn't because of
这并非因为我们寿命短，而是因为
that it was because something changed
某些因素发生了改变。而
and and and what changed was our diet
改变的因素包括我们的饮食、
was environmental toxins was our
环境毒素、
microbiome was our nutritional
微生物群以及
deficiencies because of the ultra
由于
processed food we're eating and so I've
我们食用的超加工食品而导致的营养缺乏。因此，我一直
been driven you know to both solve
致力于解决
problems individually for in for people
人们的个体
with their health as as well as take on
健康问题，同时也着手解决
our of our chronic disease which if it's
慢性疾病的根本原因，比如
food right so and and environmental
食物和环境
toxins and I and I realized that I
毒素。我意识到，我
couldn't cure diabetes in my office
无法在我的诊室里治愈糖尿病，糖尿病的根源在于
right diabetes was caused on the farm
农场
and the factories and the grocery stores
、工厂、杂货店
and the restaurants not in in my office
和餐馆，而不是我的诊室。
and so I really had to go Upstream to
所以我必须追溯源头，从根本上解决问题。
deal with the root causes of why my
我的
patients were sick because I could
病人生病了，因为我可以
change your diet and I could get them to
改变他们的饮食，让他们
be better and could fix a lot of things
好起来，解决很多问题，
but it they would just kept more people
但这样只会让更多的人
just keep coming in I'm like this is
不断来就诊。我觉得这太
ridiculous and so I realized I had to do
荒谬了，所以我意识到我必须做点什么。
something about it so I wrote a book
于是我写了一本书，
called food fix which essentially lays
叫做《食物修复》（Food Fix），这本书主要
out how food is a Nexus of everything we
阐述了食物如何成为我们所有
care about and create a nonprofit where
关心之事的纽带。我还创建了一个非营利组织，
I work in Washington to try to change
我在华盛顿工作，致力于改变
food policies like child-friendly
食品政策，比如儿童友好型
labeling and medically tailored meals
标签、定制医疗膳食、
and changing nutrition education and
改变营养教育、
changing our dietary guidelines and
改变膳食指南，以及
changing the kinds of food they aable
改变
through Snap or food stamps you know why
通过SNAP（补充营养援助计划）或食品券发放的食物种类。你知道，为什么
should we be giving you know 10% of our
我们要把1000亿美元预算的10%用于发放食品
stamps for soda which we know kills
券，而我们都知道汽水会害死
people you know it's so so I've been
人？我一直在从
the macro and the micro what what is the
宏观和微观两个层面研究这些问题。
um current state of food in your point
在你看来，目前的食物状况如何？
of view because it's difficult isn't it
因为这确实很棘手，不是吗？
especially you when we come to America
尤其是对我们这些英国人来说，来到美国后，
as Brits um I feel like we always get
感觉总是会
fat it's very very difficult to come to
发胖。来到
Los Angeles or New York where we
洛杉矶或纽约，真的很难适应。 我们
frequent as Brits to run the show yeah
英国人经常去便利店，在那里我们掌控一切，是的，
and to not get fat I'm sorry so like
而且为了不发胖，抱歉，所以，这到底是怎么回事？
what is but it's difficult like you know
你知道，
I do these podcasts about health in food
我一直在做关于健康饮食的播客，
all the time but then I I think okay
但我觉得，好吧，所有
it's all good having this all all this
这些
advice but when you walk outside and you
建议都很好，但当你走出去，
walk into a convenience store you are
走进便利店时，你就
doomed yeah yeah we live in a toxic
完了。是的，我们生活在一个充满毒素的
nutritional landscape it's a nutritional
营养环境中，这是一个营养
Wasteland a carnival of of uh enticing
荒漠，一个充斥着诱人、
colorful addictive highly processed
色彩鲜艳、令人上瘾、高度加工的
food-like substances that drive our
食品类物质的嘉年华，这些物质
biology in all the wrong ways and and so
以各种错误的方式驱动着我们的生物机能。因此，
it's very difficult to be healthy In
在
America which is why 90 3% of us have
美国保持健康非常困难，这就是为什么90.3%的美国人都有
some metabolic dysfunction this is
某种代谢功能障碍。这是
according to the we call the national
根据我们称之为“国家
health and nutrition examination survey
健康和营养调查”的数据得出的，这项调查由
the government does which is hundreds of
政府进行，对数十
thousands of people looking at their
万人进行了
blood work over many many years and
多年的血液检查。
we're messed up you know and it's it's
我们的身体状况很糟糕，你知道，这
not an accident it has to do with with
不是偶然的，而是与
the food we produce how we grow it what
我们生产的食物有关，我们如何种植，
we grow how it's processed how it's um
我们种植什么，如何加工，如何
made into different food-like substances
制成各种食品类物质。
to stay out of trouble in America I mean
在美国，除非你真的知道自己在做什么，否则很难避免惹上麻烦。我的意思是，
I I do it because I'm highly educated
我之所以能做到这一点，是因为我受过高等教育，
but it's very tough and it's easy to
但这真的很难，而且很容易
make the wrong choice how do you do it
做出错误的选择。你是怎么做到的呢？
oh well I I'm very sort of religious
哦，我对自己吃的东西非常讲究。
it's basically I mean if it's something
我的意思是，我不吃任何包装食品或加工食品，我就是不吃。这是一条铁律。基本上，如果是
that's like a can of sardines or a can
像沙丁鱼罐头或
of tomatoes obviously if it's minimally
西红柿罐头之类的，显然，如果是加工最少的
processed Foods that's fine you know
食品，那就没问题。你知道，
we've been Mally processing Foods
我们一直在加工食品，
forever sauerkraut is processed yogurt
酸菜是加工食品，
yogurt's processed that's not bad it's
酸奶也是加工食品，这本身没问题，问题在于
how it's processed and and so I I
它的加工方式。所以我完全
eliminate all Ultra processed foods I
不吃超加工食品。
if I go into a store convenience store
如果我去便利店
and I see all these different things to
看到各种各样的东西，我甚至不会把它们当成食物。 在
buy it it just it looks to me like a
我看来，它看起来就像一块
rock like the way Pro that process in my
石头。就像我脑子里那个想法一样，嗯，那根本
brain well that's not really food why
不是食物，我为什么要吃
up a rock and eat it uh so I I tried to
它？我不会捡起一块石头去吃。所以我尽量
uh cook my own food
自己做饭，
and uh I bring food with me so for
而且我还会带些食物。
example today I had another podcast I
比如今天，我之前录了另一个播客，
did earlier and I knew I wasn't going to
我知道我没
have time for lunch so I had uh earlier
时间吃午饭，所以我之前
bought some snacks and I actually have a
买了一些零食。我
a care package basically a emergency
其实还有一个应急
Snack Pack so I don't have a food
零食包，这样
emergency in my backpack all the time so
我的背包里就不会一直装着应急食物了。里面装着一天的口粮，
it's like a day's rations and that was
那就是
my lunch so basically even though I
我的午餐。所以，虽然我
eat today I I pre-planned so it takes a
今天没时间出去吃饭，但我提前做好了计划。
little planning you know like you came
你知道，这需要一点计划。就像你
to the United States from the UK you
从英国来美国，你
didn't just like leave your house and go
不会直接离开家去
to the airport you thought about what
机场，你会考虑
you're packing you brought the right
你要带什么，带上合适的
clothes you brought your crew you want
衣服，带上你的工作人员，
to bring your cameras or whatever you
带上你的相机或其他任何你需要带的东西，你
have to bring you have you have to plan
必须做好计划。
but somehow we don't think we have to do
但不知为何，我们却往往忽略了这一点。
that for our health we we have to plan
为了健康，我们必须这样做，我们必须做好计划。
it and so I'm very careful about
所以我非常注重
planning and occasion I get stuck and
计划，但偶尔也会遇到困难。
you know usually I can find some nuts or
你知道，通常我总能找到一些坚果之类的东西，
something somewhere even if they're in
即使它们浸泡在
oil that I don't like so it it's tough I
我不喜欢的油里。所以这很棘手。
got told the other day which helped me
前几天有人告诉我一件事，这让我更好地
understand myself I got told that when
理解了自己。他说，当
we're hungry especially when it's sort
我们饥饿时，尤其是在
of like late at night The Logical center
深夜，
of our brain like the pre-renal cortex
我们大脑的逻辑中心，比如肾前皮层，
is less active and the amydala the sort
活动会减少，而杏仁核——
of emotional part of our brain that
大脑中负责情感、
wants the dopamine is much more active
渴望多巴胺的部分——则会更加活跃。这
and it helped me to understand why maybe
让我明白，为什么
late at night if I haven't planned my
如果我在深夜没有计划
food um I'm much more susceptible to
好吃什么，我就更容易
make a bad food choice that I then
做出不健康的食物选择，然后
regret I'm much more acceptable to lean
后悔。我更容易接受
in for sugar or something that's like
糖分或
yeah super high in carbs or whatever
高碳水化合物之类的食物。这
yeah that really helped me and this is
真的很有帮助。这就是为什么
the why the planning thing makes a lot
计划很
of sense cuz I can use my prefrontal
重要的原因，因为我可以利用我的前额叶
cortex my logic center of my brain to
皮层——大脑的逻辑中心——
make the food choice in the morning yeah
在早上做出食物选择，
so that I don't find myself making a
这样我就不会后悔了。 我自己也犯
mistake it's so important Stephen
过错，这一点非常重要，斯蒂芬，
because people have to understand that
因为人们必须明白，
willpower is not the answer you cannot
意志力不是解决问题的办法。你不能
use willpower to control your food
用意志力控制你的饮食
Behavior it's part of your
行为，这是你
ancestral evolutionary limbic reptile
祖先进化边缘系统、爬行动物、
dinosaur brain and so when your blood
恐龙大脑的一部分。所以当你的
sugar drops you're going to eat whatever
血糖下降时，你会吃掉
in front of you if there's a vending
眼前的任何东西，无论是自动
machine if there's a donut if it's
售货机里的、甜甜圈里的还是饼干里的，即使
cookies it doesn't matter even if you
你
know better and I I've experienced this
知道不应该吃，也无所谓。我经历过这种情况，
you're just going to eat whatever
你会什么都吃，
because it's a life-threatening
因为这就像一场危及生命的
emergency your body doesn't know that
紧急情况。你的身体不知道附近有
there's grocery stores and restaurants
杂货店和餐馆，
it means you're going to go out and try
这意味着你会出去寻找食物，就像
like an emergency so when you have that
一场紧急情况。所以，当你遇到这种
food emergency and you don't have the
食物危机，而你又没有
right food on you you're in trouble I
合适的食物时，你就麻烦了。
have that all the time I have this like
我经常遇到这种情况，我
my brain is like just today break the
内心一直在挣扎，一个声音在说“做正确的事”，而另一个声音则在说“今天就
rule and and but obviously that voice is
破例一次吧”。显然，有时那个声音会更
louder sometimes than others and
响亮，
typically late at night it's louder
尤其是在深夜。
sleep deprivation stress stress sleep
睡眠不足、压力、睡眠
deprivation all that increases your
不足都会增加
appetite it increases cortisol it
食欲，增加皮质醇水平，还会让人咧嘴大笑。
is a hunger hormone I we know you can
饥饿激素，我们都知道，你可以让
take uh you know young healthy K college
年轻健康的
kids and sleep deprive them and they're
大学生睡眠不足，他们会
going to crave carbs they're going to
渴望碳水化合物和
crave sugar and they're going to gain
糖分，然后
weight it's not rocket science what
体重增加。这并不难理解。
any money at all so they can't you know
那么对于那些一无所有的人来说呢？
they don't have the ability to a lot of
他们没有能力享受我们拥有的许多
the Privileges that me and you have what
特权。在
remain healthy in a world where every
这个
convenience store is trying to sell you
便利店都在兜售
something cheap and sugary yeah a really
廉价高糖食品的世界里，为了保持健康，他们应该考虑哪些最基本的需求？嗯，这确实是个
good good question you know I think I
好问题。我
think the economics of being healthy is
认为，健康的经济性是
a problem and and and we know that
一个问题，而且我们知道
there's a huge disparity in health um
健康方面存在巨大的差距。
but it's not only economics it's
但这不仅仅是经济问题，还有
education uh you know I met with woman
教育问题。我见过
Stenson which is in Brooklyn it's a very
布鲁克林贝德斯滕森诊所的一位医生，那里是一个非常
underserved
缺乏医疗服务的
area and uh you know very um low social
地区，
economic status group very unhealthy and
社会经济地位很低，健康状况很差。
she said you know Mark you know the the
她说，马克，你知道吗，
health is it money no is education so
健康的首要预测因素是金钱吗？不，是教育。
even people who are were wealthy but
即使是富有但未
haven't been educated still have issues
受过教育的人，仍然会面临健康问题。
so for me it was really about education
所以对我来说，关键在于教育。
and so people can be educated to do the
人们可以通过教育做出
right thing and it doesn't have to be
正确的选择，而且这并不一定很
expensive and I was part of this film 10
昂贵。
years ago called fedup that looked at
十年前，我参与拍摄了一部名为《FedUp》的纪录片，探讨了
childood obesity and our food system and
儿童肥胖、我们的食品体系、
the Advent of sugar and marketing and
糖的出现、营销以及
processed foods and we we visit a lot of
加工食品的影响。我们走访了很多
families and I work with a family in
家庭，我与南卡罗来纳州伊兹利的一个家庭合作。伊兹利是
America it has the worst uh called the
美国最贫困的地区之一，拥有
deserts in America basically where
美国最严重的“食物沙漠”之一。基本上，那里
there's not a lot of healthy options to
几乎没有健康的食品
choose from oh yeah and there's
选择。对了，还有一个
something called the retail food
叫做“零售食品
environment index how many healthy
环境指数”的指标，用来衡量健康
grocery stores are there to fast food
食品杂货店与快餐店
and convenience stores and there was
和便利店的比例。伊兹利的情况非常
terrible and his family you know was
糟糕，大约是10比1。你知道，
family of five they lived in a trailer
他们一家五口每月靠1000美元的伙食费生活。
they uh were in disability in food
他们住在拖车里，靠残疾补助金生活。
stamps the mother was 100 plus pounds
母亲超重100多磅，
overweight the father was very
父亲非常
overweight had type two diabetes and was
肥胖，患有二型糖尿病，
on already at 42 year olds old was on
42岁就
dialysis for kidney
因肾衰竭开始透析，
failure which is amazing cuz you usually
这很令人惊讶，因为通常这种情况
don't see that till later the son was 16
要到年纪大了才会出现。儿子16
years old and 50% body fat guy should be
岁，体脂率高达50%（正常体脂率应该在
10 to 20 and was about di to be diabetic
10%到20%之间），而且已经接近
pre-diabetic and rather than kind of
糖尿病前期。
they were part of the movie I said why
他们并没有像电影里那样，只是简单地说“
do you want to do this they were like
你们为什么要拍这部电影”，而是直接问他们。他们说：“
well in order for my dad to get the
为了让我父亲能做
kidney transplant wait we're trying we
肾移植手术，我们正在努力，但
don't know what to do we're doing all
不知道该怎么办。我们尝试了各种
this lowfat stuff and we're doing all
低脂饮食和
this diet stuff we have in the house not
减肥方法，但家里的那些东西都没
working so I went to their house their
用。”于是我去了他们的
trailer and I rather than giving a
拖车，没有像往常那样对他们进行
lecture about what to do I said let's
说教，而是说：“我们
cook a meal together but let first Let's
一起做顿饭吧。不过，先让我看看
do an inspection of your kitchen and
你们的厨房，
let's see what's in here and so we
看看里面有什么。”于是，我们把
pulled out everything from the freezer
冰箱
and the fridge and the cupboards and
和冷冻柜里的东西都拿出来了。 橱柜里
everything was packaged boxed processed
所有东西都是包装好的，盒装的，加工过的，
fructose corn syrup from the peanut
从花生
butter to the salad dressing everything
酱到沙拉酱，所有东西都含有大量的高果糖玉米糖浆，而且都
had trans fat in it which is deadly and
含有反式脂肪，这可是致命的。
a lot of it said diet there so my basic
很多东西还标着“低脂”。所以我的基本
rule is if it has a health claim on the
原则是，如果标签上有健康声明，就
label don't eat it you know it's
别吃。你知道，无
gluten-free potato chips doesn't make it
麸质薯片并不代表它
healthy right Coca-Cola is gluten-free
健康，对吧？无麸质可口可乐也
doesn't make it healthy so um I showed
不代表它健康。所以我给
them what they were doing and I said
他们看了看他们正在做的事情，我说，
let's just make a simple meal here's a
咱们就做顿简单的饭吧。这里有一本
guide called good food on a tight budget
叫《预算有限也能吃得好》的指南，教你
how to eat well for you for the planet
如何为自己、地球
and your wallet and it's made by the
和钱包吃得好，这是
environmental working group you can get
环境工作组（EWG）编写的，可以
up on ewg.org it's free and and and it
在ewg.org上找到，是免费的。然后，他们问我，
was like how do you choose the cheaper
怎么选择便宜的
cuts of meat or the the beans or the
肉类、豆类、
grains or the veggies you know like
谷物或蔬菜？你知道，像
onions and carrots and celery are not
洋葱、胡萝卜和芹菜都不
expensive you know like a lot of veggies
贵，很多蔬菜
are not expensive so we made turkey
都不贵。所以我们做了火鸡
chili we made a salad from fresh
辣椒，还做了一份沙拉。 新鲜的
ingredients olive oil and vinegar
食材，橄榄油和醋汁，而
dressing not a dressing that was full of
不是那种充满
chemicals and high fructose corn syrup
化学物质、高果糖玉米糖浆
and refined oils we I showed them how to
和精炼油的调味汁。我教他们
roast his sweet potatoes I showed them
烤红薯，教他们
how to stir fry vegetables we had some
炒蔬菜，还吃了些
asparagus they never eaten anything
芦笋。他们以前从没吃过
fresh they never cooked in the kitchen
新鲜食物，也从没在厨房做过饭。
the kids came out who were playing video
孩子们从玩电子
games they came running in the kitchen
游戏出来，跑进厨房，问：“这是什么
like what's that smell like and it was
味道？” 原来是
like the roasting the sweet potatoes we
烤红薯的香味。我们
had this beautiful dinner together they
一起享用了一顿丰盛的晚餐，他们很
love the food and I was like you know
喜欢。我当时想，你知道吗，
what I don't know if it's going to work
我不知道这方法能不能奏效，
but you don't they didn't even have
但你也不知道。他们甚至连
cutting boards they didn't have knives
砧板都没有，也没有刀。
they like they literally had like we
他们真的只有一把黄油刀，我们
tried to cut uh the you know the um the
试着用它切
onions and the sweet potatoes with a
洋葱和红薯，
butter knife cuz that's all they had it
因为他们只有
was like a butter knife it was really
黄油刀，真的
hard W uh so I bought them on the way
很难切。所以，
home I bought them cutting boards on
回家的路上，我在
Amazon and on knes and I sent it to
亚马逊和Knes上给他们买了砧板，然后寄到了
their house next week the mom text me
他们家。下周，他们妈妈给我发短信说：“
she says Mark we lost 18 pounds this
马克，我们这周瘦了18磅。”
week as a family A year later the father
一年后，父亲
lost 45 got a new kidney the mother lost
减重45磅，做了肾移植手术；母亲减重
100 pound the son lost 132 lbs and and
100磅；儿子减重132磅，并
went to medical school first guy in his
考上了医学院，成为家中第一个上大学的人。
family to go to college and he asked me
他曾向我请教
for a letter recommendation for medical
医学院的推荐信。
school and they lived in one of the
他们住在
worst Food deserts they didn't have much
食物匮乏的地区，
you know economically and they were able
经济条件很差，但他们最终找到了解决办法。
to figure it out because eating real
因为吃真正的
food doesn't have to be expensive you
食物并不一定很贵，你
don't have to have a $70 wagu ribeye
不需要花70美元买一块和牛肋眼
steak right you can you can eat real
牛排，对吧？你可以吃真正的
food and it's just as simple as not
食物，其实很简单，只要
eating the ultr processed food it's so
不吃那些超加工食品就行了。这些食品
bad for us and it kills 11 million
对我们非常有害，
people a year we know the state is so
每年导致1100万人死亡。我们知道，这些食品的危害非常
strong it causes mental health issues
大，会导致心理健康问题、
aggression violence depression and
攻击性、暴力、抑郁和焦虑，以及
anxiety uh gun violence I mean the
枪支暴力。相关的
studies are there I just I did a podcast
研究有很多，我最近在
on the Doctor's Pharmacy my podcast
我的播客节目“医生药房”上做了一期
about this talking about how our food is
关于这个话题的播客，讨论了我们的食物是如何
affecting our mental health not just
影响我们的心理健康的，不仅仅是
obesity and diabetes but our cognitive
肥胖和糖尿病，还有我们的认知
function uh add and memory issues I mean
功能，比如注意力缺陷障碍和记忆力问题。
it's all linked to what we're eating so
这一切都与……有关。 我们正在吃饭，所以
we we have a you know like I said the
我们……你知道，就像我说的，无论
best of times the worst of times we know
好坏，我们都知道该
what to do but we have the ability to do
怎么做，而且我们有能力去做，只是……这只是
it it it's just it's just a problem of
一个
Education a problem of a political will
教育问题，一个缺乏政治意愿
to change the policies that are driving
去改变那些驱使
us to do the wrong thing and right now
我们做错事的政策的问题。现在
Congress that would limit as a pilot
国会正在提议一项法案，作为试点项目，限制领取
Ultra processed food for kids with food
食品券的儿童购买超加工食品，
stamps which I think would be
我认为这
amazing the food industry is fighting
很棒。食品行业正在拼死反击，对吧？
back tooth and nail right so so we're
所以我们正在与
fighting big forces food industry is the
强大的势力作斗争。食品行业是
planet when I was growing up um and I
地球上最大的产业。在我小时候，为了保持
was trying to be healthy one of the
健康，
things I used to do was chug milk yeah
我以前经常做的一件事就是狂喝牛奶，
because
因为有人
I got told that it would make me tall
告诉我喝牛奶能让我长得
like my brothers so I used to drink milk
像我哥哥们一样高，所以我以前疯狂地喝牛奶，
like crazy yeah straight from the carton
直接从纸盒里喝，
just as many gulps as I could take from
从冰箱里拿出来就喝，能喝多少就喝多少。这有用吗？你长高了吗？
grow I have no idea I'm still shorter
我不知道，我现在还是比
than they are so I guess not um but
他们矮，所以我想应该没用。但这是
that's one of the big myths that I think
我认为
a lot of families still believe that
很多家庭仍然相信的一个很大的误区，那就是
milk is great for our bones and to help
牛奶对我们有益。 牛奶能强健骨骼，还能帮助
us grow what's your thoughts on milk
我们成长，你对牛奶有什么看法？嗯，牛奶也是个
yeah so uh you controversial topic as
有争议的话题。是的，我的
well yes I mean the dairy industry is
意思是，乳制品行业规模
Big um our current Secretary of
庞大。我们现任的
agriculture worked for the dairy
农业部长就曾在乳制品
industry it's problematic because
行业工作过。这很成问题，
because the science isn't there there
因为缺乏科学依据。有
was a there was a paper called milk in
一篇名为《牛奶与
health that was published in the New
健康》的论文发表在《新
England Journal of Medicine top medical
英格兰医学杂志》上，这可以说是世界顶级的医学
journal in the world arguably maybe the
期刊，
lanet if you're from the
如果你来自
UK but it it basically was written by
英国，或许会称之为《伦敦邮报》。这篇论文基本上是由
two Harvard scientists that dissected
两位哈佛大学的科学家撰写的，他们剖析了
all the scientific evidence around milk
所有关于牛奶的科学证据，
and whether the claims were right or not
并分析了这些说法是否正确。
and just maybe for the audience in
也许
Europe you might not know this but in
欧洲的听众不知道这件事，但在
the states you'll remember this there
美国，你们应该还记得，当时有
were all these got milk ads so there
很多“喝牛奶”的广告，很多
were famous people celebrities uh you
名人、明星、
know Sports athletes politicians all
运动员、政客都
wearing a white milk mustache and
戴着白色的牛奶胡子，为“
they're like got milk as a promotion and
喝牛奶”做宣传。
and and In Those ads it would say it's
这些广告宣称牛奶能
going to build better bones it's going
强健骨骼，能
to do this it's going to do that and the
做到这样那样。
FTC the Federal Trade
联邦贸易
Commission uh actually or I think it was
委员会（FTC）……呃，或者我记得是
Federal say you can't do that because
联邦…… 不能那样做，因为
it's it's not true like you have to take
这不是真的，就像你必须
those ads out so the ads went away and
撤下那些广告一样。广告确实消失了，但实际上
it was the government promoting Those
是政府
ads with the dairy Council so there's
与乳制品委员会合作推广这些广告。
the government has where it's supposed
政府有一个叫做“结账计划”的项目，旨在
to support agriculture well the
支持农业。然而，政府却
ads with taxpayer dollars and the
用纳税人的钱部分支付了这些广告的费用，而且并
science wasn't there and the the dietary
没有科学依据。
guidelines for Americans says that the
美国膳食指南建议，
have two glasses of milk a day to be
为了健康，普通美国人每天应该喝三杯牛奶，儿童每天应该喝两杯牛奶。
for school lunches in America without
在美国，如果学校午餐
having milk on the menu now there is no
菜单上没有牛奶，就无法获得资金。然而，没有任何
evidence to support this in fact there's
证据支持这种说法。事实上，有
opposite evidence that skin milk causes
相反的证据表明，牛奶会导致
weight gain because it doesn't satisfy
体重增加，因为它无法满足
your appetite that milk can cause cancer
食欲；牛奶会导致癌症，
that prate cancer prostate cancer that U
比如前列腺癌；牛奶并
it doesn't create strong bones in fact
不能强健骨骼，事实上，
high milk drinkers that it creates a lot
大量饮用牛奶的人骨折的风险更高；牛奶会引发许多
of digestive issues for people it can
消化问题；牛奶还会
create autoimmune diseases like type 1
导致自身免疫性疾病，比如1型
diabetes it has common allergies or food
糖尿病；牛奶还会导致常见的过敏或食物不
sensitivities that people get
耐受。
and I remember I was I was in the um
我记得我当时…… 有
emergency room once and when I was
一次我
working in the ER and this mother comes
在急诊室工作，一位母亲
in with this kid with like you know had
带着孩子进来，孩子已经
like this 10th ear infection fews I was
耳部感染好几次了，大概是第十次吧。我问她发生了
like what happened like when did this
什么事，什么时候
start oh it started when he was like 12
开始的。她说，大概从他12个
months old I said what changed well I
月大的时候开始。我说，是什么改变了？她说，我
stopped breastfeeding and I started
停止了母乳喂养，开始
giving him milk and all of a sudden he
给他喝牛奶，然后突然间他就
started getting these ear infections I'm
开始耳部感染。我说，
like oh this is before I even knew about
哦，这都是在我了解这些之前的事了。
all this it was just kind of an
这只是一个
interesting footnote but we really have
有趣的插曲。但我们真的需要
have to look at the data and be
关注数据，以
science-driven and the problem is we're
科学为依据。问题是，
we're we have corporate capture in
在美国，企业已经
has captured our food agencies our
掌控了我们的食品机构，食品行业控制了我们的
political um system from the FDA to the
政治体系，从FDA到
USDA they spend for example half a
USDA。例如，他们
billion dollars just on the farm bill uh
仅在农业法案上就花费了5亿美元，其中包括
which has you know for example food
食品
stamps and other food programs child
券和其他食品项目，以及婴
infant nutrition so it's it's really
幼儿营养。这真的很
unfortunate but milk is not Nature's
不幸，但牛奶并不是大自然的
perfect food it's only Nature's perfect
完美食物，它只适合
calf is there health benefits to milk
小牛。牛奶对健康有益吗？是的。
yes so so that's the other side of it
这就是问题的另一面。那么，
right if we're drinking modern milk
如果我们喝的是现代牛奶，我们应该喝什么牛奶呢？
modern milk is from wholen cows that are
现代牛奶来自
almost homogen ins same not homogenized
几乎同质化的奶牛，不是均质化的
milk but homogeneous breed they have
牛奶，而是同质化的品种。这些奶牛的
very few bows inseminating them they
授精数量很少，它们采用
have like you know massive insemination
大规模的人工授精
program from very
计划，
few bulls that have a limited genetic
使用基因有限的少数公牛。这些奶牛被
stock and uh they're what we call A1
称为A1型
cows so most heirloom cows most sort of
奶牛。而大多数传统
historical Dairy had something called A2
奶牛，也就是大多数历史悠久的奶牛，都含有一种叫做A2型
casine Which is less inflamm fatory less
酪蛋白的物质，这种物质炎症性较低，不易
likely to cause gut issues less
引起肠道问题，
problematic for the body so sheep and
对身体的危害也较小。绵羊
goat milk have A2 certain cows like
奶和山羊奶含有A2型酪蛋白，某些奶牛，比如
Jersey or gery cows have A2 in them and
泽西牛或格雷伊牛，也含有A2型酪蛋白。
now um and and so this A1 casine is
现在你可以买到A2型牛奶，甚至A2型冰淇淋。所以，这种A1型酪蛋白
potentially very problematic so I think
可能存在很大的问题。我认为
the current Dairy is not great and then
目前的奶牛养殖方式并不理想，因为
we pasteurize it and homogenize it and
我们会对牛奶进行巴氏杀菌和均质化处理，还会给
EST Esten that we add into the cows it's
奶牛添加生长激素，比如雌二醇（EST）。
in the milk we have 60 different
牛奶里含有60多种不同的
hormones in the milk some of them are
激素，其中一些是
naturally occurring but we milk uh
天然存在的，但我们挤的是
pregnant cows and that milk has a lot
怀孕母牛的奶，这种奶的
more hormonal effects so I think current
激素含量更高。所以我认为，目前
current Dairy is not something we should
我们不应该大量
consume now if you have a chance to get
食用乳制品。如果你有机会喝到
sheep milk or goat milk or A2 milks from
绵羊奶、山羊奶或A2型牛奶，
a cow that may be okay yogurts may be
那或许可以，酸奶也可能可以，但这也
okay it depends on your genetics too 75%
要看你的基因。世界上75%的人
the world's lactose intolerant many
乳糖不耐受，很多
people have dairy sensitivities but uh I
人对乳制品过敏。但我
think you know if it's if it's the right
认为，如果
Source it's okay for example I use goat
来源正确，就没问题。例如，我早上喝Goat
way as my morning protein shake so goat
Way蛋白奶昔，Goat
way is from goats obviously uh there's
Way显然是用山羊奶做的，酪蛋白含量
very little casine in it but it's A2
很低，即使
casc if there's any and I don't react to
有，也是A2型酪蛋白。我对Goat Way没有反应，
it but if I have regular way I do have a
但如果喝普通牛奶，我就会有
reaction I get congested I'll get
反应，比如鼻塞、长痘痘等等。
pimples or I get regular stuff so I
所以，我
don't think Dair is something we should
认为我们不应该
be consuming in large amounts unless
大量食用乳制品，除非……
it's certain kinds of dairy what do you
是某些类型的乳制品，你
think of um this conversation at the
觉得怎么样？嗯，目前
moment around a zmac it seems like it's
关于ZMAC的讨论似乎
just exploded in yeah culture I mean the
在文化领域爆发了，我的意思是，
share price of the company that maker
生产ZMAC的公司的股价
zenek has gone through the roof yeah in
已经飙升，是的，这种程度的涨幅
a way that I've just never seen in
在生物技术领域是我前所未见的。嗯，似乎
there's no apparent side effects if you
没有明显的副作用，如果你
ask
问
people they struggle to T any side
人们，他们很难说有任何
effects but I actually think I saw you
副作用。但我确实看到你
make a video about it if I'm yeah yeah
做过一个关于它的视频，如果我没记错的话，是的，是的，关于它，
your thoughts on his imp um you crossed
你对它有什么看法？嗯，你抱起了
your arms are you going to get yourself
胳膊，你不会给自己
trouble just like well I'm trying not to
惹麻烦吧？就像……好吧，我尽量不
bang the
拍桌子，
but first of all we have a massive
但首先，我们面临着严重的
obesity problem and we don't have any
肥胖问题，而且我们没有任何
good Solutions and so something comes
好的解决方案，所以出现了一种
once a week that makes you not hungry
每周注射一次的产品，它可以让你不饿，
and bypasses your normal biological
绕过你正常的生物
mechanisms and you lose
机制，从而
weight that's a
减肥，这
huge attractive thing and that's why NOA
非常有吸引力，这就是为什么
Nordisk is the biggest company now in
诺德公司现在是丹麦最大的公司，
Denmark it's the biggest uh part of the
它占
GDP of Denmark I don't know if they
丹麦GDP的最大份额。 我不知道
leave allow it in Denmark they're the
丹麦是否允许使用这种药，他们是生产
people that make oek yeah people that
OEC的人，是的，就是
make OIC and uh recently the CEO of Nova
生产OIC的人。最近，
Nordisk who makes OIC publicly said he
OIC的生产商诺和诺德的首席执行官公开表示，他
was getting calls from processed food
接到了很多加工食品
manufacturers very concerned because
制造商的电话，他们非常担心，因为
their market share was dropping and they
他们的市场份额正在下降，他们
were very concerned that it was going to
非常担心这会
affect their business think about that
影响他们的业务。想想看，
so I think oing is effective it works
所以我认为OIC是有效的，它
with a natural part of your biology uh
与你
called glp1 which is something your body
体内一种叫做GLP-1的天然物质相互作用，这种物质是人体自身
makes uh and we can can make more of it
产生的，我们可以
by doing lots of different things from
通过很多不同的方法来增加它的含量，从
certain probiotics and bacteria arot to
某些益生菌和细菌到
certain foods uh to certain ways of
某些食物，再到某些饮食方式。
eating but the effect of the drug is
但是这种药物的效果
very strong just for context for anyone
非常强。为了方便那些
that doesn't know what a zenek is let's
不知道OEC是什么的人，我来解释一下：
give them some context well it's it's a
它是一种
drug that's was first Ed for
最初用于治疗
diabetes and then it it works by acting
糖尿病的药物，它的作用机制是通过作用
on a pathway called gp1 glucagon like
于一种叫做GP1（胰高血糖素样
pep peptide one which is just a pathway
肽-1）的通路，这是一种
and it and it and it regulates insulin
调节胰岛素
function it regulates weight
功能、体重
uh and appetite and so it really works
和食欲的通路。所以它确实有效。 它原本是
to help with blood
为了帮助控制
sugar but the side effect was weight
血糖，但副作用是
loss so it was like we studied Viagra
减肥，这就好比我们研究伟哥是
for blood pressure but the side effect
为了降低血压，结果发现
was it helped men with tions so it was
它还能帮助男性缓解性欲。所以，
like well it's like kind of like that
嗯，有点像那样，对吧？
right it was like wasn't designed for
它原本不是为
this but it actually had the side effect
这个目的设计的，但实际上却有这个副作用。
and you know since obesity affects so
你知道，肥胖影响着
many people there's now two billion
很多人，现在地球上有20亿
people on the planet who are overweight
人超重。
so you take this injection yeah and you
所以，你注射这种药，
basically your appetite drops out so you
基本上你的食欲就会下降，
don't you don't feel hungry you don't
你不会感到饥饿，不会
feel as hungry and you can feel nauseous
那么饿，你可能会感到恶心、呕吐，
you can throw up you can not want to eat
不想吃东西。
and and people stop it because of the
人们因为这些副作用而停止使用。
side effects so those are short-term
这些都是短期
side effects um what it so the plus side
副作用。它的优点是
effective it has some metabolic benefits
有效，减肥确实有一些代谢方面的好处，这对
when you lose weight which can help your
你的
health benefits I don't think it's the
健康有益。我不认为真正
drug that's having the health benefits
有益健康的是药物本身，而是
it's the weight loss but there's a lot
减肥。但它也有很多
of downsides one uh it costs not a lot
缺点，首先，它很贵。
of money so if you were to put everybody
所以，如果你要给每个人注射， 如果
who's overweight in the country on it it
全国所有超重的人都服用这种药物，花费将高达
would be $5.1 trillion so it's an
5.1万亿美元，这笔
enormous enormously cost how much does
费用简直是天文数字。
it cost like $13 to $700 a month 13 to
每月费用大概在13美元到700美元之间，甚至13美元到
$1,700 a month a month which is like you
1700美元之间，相当于减掉
know probably you know 1,500 pound or
1500磅（约680公斤）的体重，这可是一笔巨款，而且是长期服用。
every month forever right when you stop
一旦停药，
it the weight gain comes back unless you
除非你
really rigorously change your lifestyle
彻底改变生活方式，否则体重就会反弹。
so it's not a lifestyle change program
所以，这并非生活方式改变计划，
it's not a this doesn't help you change
它并不能帮助你改变
your behavior or habits it's it's a
行为或习惯，而是一种
pharmacological appetite straight jacket
药物性的食欲控制手段。
and and that can be effective if you if
如果
some people really need it they need it
某些人真的需要，它或许有效。
if some people are mass overweight and
比如，一些严重超重且不
they don't want to get a gastric bypass
想做胃旁路手术的人，
I think it may be okay but here's the
我觉得这种药物可能还可以接受。但缺点是：
rup one you have to take it forever two
第一，你必须终身服用；第二，
it's expensive three most uh uh of
它很贵；第三，大多数
people are not aware that not only do
人没有意识到，
you lose fat but you lose muscle so
你减掉的不仅仅是脂肪，还有肌肉，
about 50% of the weight you lose is
大约50%的体重都是
muscle and muscle is where your
肌肉。 肌肉是
metabolism is it burns seven times the
新陈代谢的源泉，它燃烧的热量是
calories as fat and you need it for
脂肪的七倍，对
longevity and health and so when you
长寿和健康至关重要。因此，一旦
lose muscle your whole Health declines
失去肌肉，你的整体健康状况就会下降，肌肉
it's Center of your health and it's very
是健康的基石，而且
tough to get that back so you have to
很难恢复。所以，
hit the gym hard with weights if you're
如果你要
going to be on a drug like OIC longer
长期服用像阿片类药物（OIC）这样的药物，就必须大幅增加蛋白质摄入，并进行高强度的举重训练。虽然这种情况是
term and that that can be managed but
可以控制的，但
it's it's most people don't right that
大多数人并没有这样做。
can be managed and you need to be
你需要定期进行双能X射线吸收法（
tracked with dexas scans and body
DEXA）扫描和身体
composition testing and really know what
成分测试，真正了解
you're doing because it can really mess
自己在做什么，因为药物可能会严重影响你的健康。虽然
you up and then you you lose the weight
体重减轻了，
but then your metabolism is slower at
但你的新陈代谢在
the end of that process than it was
这个过程结束时会比开始之前更慢，
before you started because you've lost
因为你失去了
your metabolic engine which is your
代谢引擎——
muscle the other thing that happens and
肌肉。另一个问题是，
we're now seeing this because it's it's
我们现在才看到这种情况，因为这种药物出现的时间
not been around that long right there
并不长。
Journal years ago that said be sure to
几年前，《新英格兰医学杂志》上有一篇文章指出，一定要在
use new drugs as soon as they come out
新药上市后尽快使用，以免
before the side effects develop right so
副作用显现。
now we're seeing two three years out
现在，我们已经看到两三年了。
serious side effects so you know we in
严重的副作用。你知道，在
medicine when we see an effect of 20 or
医学领域，当我们
30% on a study we go that's that's a
在一项研究中看到20%或30%的效果时，我们会认为这是件
great thing let's you know statens lower
好事。比如，史泰龙能降低
heart disease by 20 to 30% great number
20%到30%的心脏病
world the side effect profile in this is
风险，是世界上最好的药物。然而，这种药物的副作用却令人
scary because bow obstruction which is
担忧。例如，肠梗阻（这
not a trivial thing essentially where
可不是小事，本质上就是
your bowels stop moving and you need
肠道停止蠕动，需要
surgery to release them is is increased
手术疏通）的风险增加了
450% pancre pancreatitis which is not a
450%；胰腺炎（这可不是什么
fun condition which is where your
好病，
pancreas becomes inflamed that affects
胰腺发炎会影响消化、
your digestion it affects your insulin
胰岛素分泌，影响身体
affects everything and you can die from
各方面，甚至可能致命）的风险
it is increased by
增加了
900% so these are not trivial things
900%。这些都不是小事。此外，还有
there's other side effects kidney and so
其他副作用，比如肾脏损伤等等。
forth so I think the longer this is out
我认为，这种药物上市时间越长，
there we're going to see more and more
我们会看到越来越多的不良
consequences of this drug and I think it
后果。而且，我认为它
misses the real issue which is how do we
忽略了真正的问题，那就是如何
fix the problem causing this it's not an
解决导致这些问题的根本原因。这并非是维生素C缺乏症，比如
weight gain obesity is not a zic
体重增加或肥胖。肥胖并非维生素C
deficiency is because of our toxic
缺乏症，而是我们有毒的
environment lifestyle food system lack
环境、生活方式和饮食造成的。 系统
of exercise environmental toxins it's
缺乏运动、环境毒素等等，情况很
complicated and and and it's not it's
复杂，而且并
not an easy fix and it requires policy
非易事，需要政策
change it requires us to rethink our
变革，需要我们重新思考
agricultural system our food processing
农业系统、食品加工
and Manufacturing system it requires
和制造系统，需要
massive education for people what to eat
对人们进行大规模的健康教育，告诉他们应该吃什么，
it requires us really to make widescale
需要我们真正地
change in our society which is going to
在社会上进行广泛的变革，这将给
cause significant loss for a lot of
很多公司带来巨大的损失。
I mean like I said the food industry is
我的意思是，就像我说的，食品行业是
the biggest industry in the world it's s
世界上最大的产业，
16 to 17 trillion dollar a year industry
年产值高达16到17万亿美元，比
most countries or I think of like I mean
大多数国家的GDP都高，比如
the entire United States is is I think
整个美国的GDP就达到了
16 trillion so it's it's a it's a big
16万亿美元。这是一个庞大的
industry with a lot to lose and and so
产业，损失巨大。因此，对于为了
for us to become healthy so taking this
健康而必须做出的改变，存在着很大的阻力。服用这种
drug seems great and and I think it's
药物看起来很棒，我认为它确实
it's it's got benefits but it's it's not
有好处，但它并非完全没有
just a risk-free solution it's funny
风险。有趣的是，
because it it feels like it's a window
感觉这就像一扇通往
into the future of how we're going to
未来
treat things like obesity because the
治疗肥胖等疾病的窗口，因为
the price hope not I well play this
价格……希望不会……好吧，我预测一下，
forward the price is going to come down
价格会下降，
because more companies are going to
因为会有更多公司
release very similar iterations that
推出类似的产品，对
cause the same effect on gp1 the price
GP1产生相同的效果。价格
will come down so quickly there'll be
会迅速下降，肯定会出现
this kind of price race I'm sure I I
价格战。我
imagine a zek got ahead of the pack
猜Zek之所以能领先，是
because they ran the clinical trials so
因为他们进行了临床试验，
they invested all that money which they
投入了大量资金，而且他们
got approved first that window's going
率先获得了批准。但这个窗口期会
to close and then the price comes down
关闭，然后价格就会下降。
and then I don't know if do they
我不知道医生会不会开这种药，
prescribe it here and conductors
或者说，医生会不会开这种药。
prescribe oh sure anybody can prescribe
哦，当然，任何人都可以开。是的，
it yeah oh really okay oh yeah so it can
真的吗？好的。哦，是的，所以
be subsidized by your insurance or
你的保险可以补贴吗？
something no no it can't be I mean the
不，不行。我的意思是，
most insurance don't pay for it they
大多数保险公司不支付这种药的费用。
might pay for it if you're diabetic but
如果你是糖尿病患者，他们可能会支付，但
for non-approved indications they they
对于未经批准的适应症，他们
typically don't pay for it now there
通常不支付。现在有
rovi which is the approved version and
Rovi，它是已获批准的版本，
and some insurance will pay some
有些保险公司会支付，有些则
insurance won't but it it's not
不会，但这并不是
something they're excited to pay about
什么…… 他们很兴奋地谈论这个
interesting why do you know this one
有趣的事情。为什么你知道你提到的那些
those side effects that you named for
副作用？你提到的那些副作用与
link to zek what is it about the drug
Zek有关。这种药物到底有什么作用会
that's causing that because I was
导致这些副作用？因为我就在
wondering as you're saying it I like is
想，就像你刚才说的，是
that because people start eating less or
因为人们开始吃得少，还是药物
is it the chemical itself no no it's the
本身的化学成分导致的？不，不，是
it's the effect of the drug it it
药物的作用。它会使
thickens the bowel wall it it it has
肠壁增厚，它会影响
effect on the gut so it is working on
肠道，所以它作用于
the gut in in a lot of the the hormones
肠道，影响肠道的许多激素
and the metabolic functions of the gut
和代谢功能，从而
are affected by OIC in ways that change
改变肠道
its functions
功能，
and and slow the emptying and do a lot
减缓排空速度，并产生许多
of things So eventually it seems to
其他影响。所以最终，它似乎会给
cause problems for a lot of people
很多人带来问题。这很
interesting because you know the
有意思，因为你知道，
positive at the moment these drugs come
目前外界对这些药物的评价非常积极，
along and it's it's like there's no side
好像它们没有任何
effects and they're super millions of
副作用，而且还有数百万
dollars of advertising and billions of
美元的广告投入和数十亿
dollars of Revenue at stake so yeah you
美元的收入。所以，是的，
nobody's talking about the bad side
没有人谈论它的坏处。这很
interesting and by the way they're
有意思。顺便说一句，他们正在
thinking of giving it to 5-year-old kids
考虑给5岁的孩子服用，
which is just terrifying to me uh for
这对我来说简直太可怕了。 就
life
人生而言，
I do think with these things there's no
我认为
such thing as a free lunch is there in
世上没有免费的午餐，对吧？
life so I think we'll eventually figure
所以我觉得我们最终会找到权衡取舍的方法。
out what the trade-off is yeah and then
然后
people can decide for themselves if the
人们可以
trade-off is worth it based on their own
根据自身
circumstan yeah I mean listen people go
情况来决定这种权衡是否值得。是的，我的意思是，听着，有些人会说“
like I want to lose 5 pounds and I don't
我想减掉5磅”，但我
think that's a good idea if you're
认为如果你
severely obese person you have severe
严重肥胖，或者有严重的
health conditions you're really
健康问题，或者你真的
struggling to get going you know it can
很难开始行动，那这不是个好主意。减肥可以作为
it be a helpful Aid absolutely you know
一种辅助手段吗？当然可以。但是，减肥
should it be given to everybody who
应该给所有想在
wants to look good for a party or a
派对或婚礼上看起来漂亮的人吗？
wedding absolutely not
绝对不应该。
what's your um position on fruit I love
你对水果的看法是什么？我喜欢
fruit how much fruit I I think it
水果，但要吃多少？我认为这
depends right so if you're a diabetic uh
取决于情况。如果你是糖尿病患者，
and you're metabolically
你的新陈代谢
completely out of whack um and you don't
完全紊乱，而且
have any metabolic
没有任何代谢
resilience you know eating a plum might
恢复能力，那么吃个李子可能
be a problem for you and now we have
对你来说就是个问题。现在我们有了
continuous glucose monitors you can
持续血糖监测仪，你可以
track your blood sugar and see and i'
追踪你的血糖，看看会发生什么。
I've had patients like this ge I I I eat
我遇到过这样的病人，我吃了
a plum and my sugar goes to the roof so
一个李子，我的血糖就…… 糖分会飙升，
but if I eat an apple it doesn't so I
但如果我吃个苹果就不会，所以我
think different fruits have different
认为不同的水果
effects on you uh but for most part
对身体的影响也不同。不过，大多数
fruit is full of phytochemicals fiber
水果富含植物化学物质、纤维和植物
phytonutrients it does have a little bit
营养素，虽然也含有少量
of sugar in it uh I would say no fruit
糖分。至于果汁，我
juice I think fruit juice is definitely
觉得不建议喝。果汁肯定
linked to obesity and kids and other
与肥胖、儿童健康以及其他一些
things but if you want to have an apple
问题有关。但如果你想吃个苹果
or a peach or a plum it's fine I think
、桃子或李子，没问题。不过，我认为
you shouldn't have it first thing in the
你不应该在早上起来第一件事就吃这些。
morning I think protein and fat in the
我认为早上摄入蛋白质和脂肪很
morning is important because it it
重要，因为它们可以
activates your metabolism and your
激活你的新陈代谢和
protein synthesis if you eat sugar in
蛋白质合成。如果你早上吃糖，而
the morning which is essentially what we
我们
eat in the world today cereal pancakes
现在吃的基本上都是糖，比如麦片、煎饼、华夫饼、松饼、百吉饼、
sweetened yogurts sweetened coffees I
加糖的酸奶、加糖的咖啡等等，那对我们身体的生理机能来说简直
mean it's the worst possible thing we
是最糟糕的事情。
can do for our biology it it jacks up
它会飙升
our blood sugar and insulin and ends up
我们的血糖和胰岛素水平，最终
causing us to gain weight and be hungry
导致我们体重增加、饥饿感增强，
and you know be craving more stuff so
并且渴望摄入更多食物。所以，吃
having having um fruit for example you
水果，比如你吃的
have frozen berries in your so I had
冷冻浆果，我早上吃的是
Frozen cherries for example in my Whey
冷冻的。 例如，在我的乳清
Protein that's okay because there's
蛋白粉里加樱桃是可以的，因为
protein in there it mitigates the effect
里面含有蛋白质，可以减轻副作用。
so what about eating times when to eat
那么，什么时候吃东西呢？
yeah have you got any thoughts around
你对我们应该什么时候吃、什么时候不吃有什么想法吗？
for sure I think you know you know we
当然，我想你知道，
had something called breakfast before
以前我们有一种叫做早餐的东西，
which was breaking the
它打破了
fast and now people eat all night they
禁食期。现在人们整夜都在吃，一直吃到
eat till they go to bed and they soon
睡觉，然后早上醒来就吃东西，
they wake up they eat or have something
或者吃一些
sugary stuff in the morning they get
含糖的东西，喝
sugary coffee and they don't get
含糖咖啡，他们没有给
themselves a window of fasting which is
自己一个禁食窗口，这
critical for our biology and I wrote
对我们的生理机能至关重要。我
about this in my book Young Forever
在我的书《永葆青春》里写过这个，
where we talked about how do we have our
我们讨论了如何启动我们
own repair re renewal system kick in cuz
自身的修复和更新系统。
the body think about it uh Stephen your
想想看，斯蒂芬，
body when you cut yourself heals the
当你割伤自己时，你的身体会愈合，
skin closes it heals how does it know
皮肤会闭合，它会愈合。它是怎么知道该怎么
how to do that right it's it's so smart
做的呢？它非常聪明，
it's got a your bones break it heals
它有自己的系统。你的骨头断了也会愈合，对吧？
right I broke my a few years ago it just
我几年前骨折了，它就愈合了，对吧？这是怎么回事？
healed right what's going on I'm not
我不会去问“
going would you please heal in there it
请你帮我愈合一下”吧。它
knows what to do it recruits stem cells
知道该怎么做，它会调动干细胞。 细胞会
it recruits repair factors and growth
募集修复因子和生长
factors and it it knows what to do so
因子，并且它知道该怎么做。所以
the body has this innate healing repair
人体拥有这种与生俱来的愈合、修复、
renewal and regeneration system and we
更新和再生系统，我们
need to learn how to activate it and
需要学习如何激活它。然而，
most of us do the opposite we do
我们大多数人却恰恰相反，
everything in our power to deactivate it
竭尽全力地让它失活，
and that causes disease so food is the
这会导致疾病。因此，食物是
most important thing we do to interact
我们
with these regenerative renewal repair
与这些再生、更新和修复
systems it's one one of the things we
系统互动最重要的途径。这是我们
call the Hallmarks of aging and there's
所说的衰老标志之一，另一个标志
one called deregulated nutrient sensing
叫做营养感知失调。它与
and it really relates to how our bodies
我们的身体
relate to food how our nutrient sensing
如何与食物互动密切相关。我们的营养感知
systems are disregulated by our highly
系统会因为高度
processed diet by high sugar and starch
加工的饮食、高糖高淀粉
and not enough of the right Foods so so
以及缺乏足够的健康食物而失调。所以，
in the in the long answer to your
长话短说，对于你的
question you know it's important to give
问题，重要的是给
yourself a break of 12 hours so if you
自己12小时的休息时间。如果你
eat at 6 at night you could eat 6 in the
晚上6点吃东西，那么
morning minimum but best probably 14 so
至少早上6点也要吃，最好是14小时。也就是说，
if you eat dinner at 600 eat breakfast
如果你6点吃晚餐，8点吃早餐，
at 8 that's okay that's a 14-hour fast
这可以，这样就是14小时的禁食。
and in that time your body is doing its
在这段时间里，你的身体会进行
clean up recycling repair is there an
清理、循环和修复。这其中是否存在
evolutionary story here for sure
进化论的解释呢？ 当然，
absolutely you know when when uh you
你知道，以前
know we didn't have grocery stores we
我们没有杂货店，
didn't have you know Whole Foods we
没有全食超市，
didn't have restaurants we didn't have
没有餐馆，没有
takeout we didn't have convenience
外卖，也没有便利
stores so we had to go out and find food
店，所以我们必须出门找吃的。
you I just came back from Tanzania and
我刚从坦桑尼亚回来，
visited the hunter gatherers there the
拜访了那里的狩猎采集部落——
kazza which is one of the last few
卡扎部落，它是仅存的几个仍然以狩猎和
tribes that hunt and gather and we went
采集为生的部落之一。我们体验了
hunting and Gathering I was like man
狩猎和采集，我当时就想，天哪，
it's a lot of work to go you know dig up
这可真够累的，你知道，挖
some roots and kill a bird in the tree
些根茎，打死树上的鸟，
and like it was it was a project we ran
简直就是个大工程，我们跑来跑去好几个
around for hours uh and and so we don't
小时。而且，我们不
know where we're getting our next meal
知道下一顿饭在哪里，
and so the body has had to deal with
所以我们的身体
periods of feast and famine before so
以前就经历过饥荒和丰收交替的时期。因此，
what it's got built into it is a system
它体内有一种
of conservation and and and repair when
储存和修复系统，当
we don't eat and so the system gets
我们不进食时，这个系统就会被
activated that improves our our blood
激活，改善我们的
sugar control that recruits new
血糖控制，募集和
mitochondria and builds new mitochondria
构建新的线粒体，
that reduces inflammation that activates
减少炎症，激活
um cellular cleanup and repair processes
细胞清理。 身体的修复过程
like digestor almost like a little
就像一个小型消化器，就像一个小型
vacuum cleaner that goes and sucks this
吸尘器，它会把这些衰老细胞和受损蛋白质全部吸入体内，然后
all up and then digest it and then uses
消化并利用其中的
the parts it's almost like a a recycling
成分。这就像
system in the body we need to activate
身体的一个回收系统，我们需要激活
that and so that fasting period is a
它。禁食期就是激活这个系统的
time to do that and we've seen even for
时间。例如，我们看到一些
concentration camp survivors who live
集中营幸存者
really long like they live 90 100 plus
非常长寿，他们中的许多人活到了90岁甚至100
years old many of them and it's because
岁以上，这是因为
they had this period of deep starvation
他们经历过一段深度饥饿期，这段时期
that had an effect on their biology and
对他们的生理机能产生了影响。
we know this we know this from many
我们从许多
animal studies that starvation and
动物研究中得知，饥饿和
fasting will extend your life by a third
禁食可以延长三分之一的寿命。
if you eat a third less calories you'll
如果你少摄入三分之一的卡路里，你的寿命就会延长三分之一。
live a third longer now it's not fun
这听起来并不轻松，对吧？
right but you don't have to do that so
但你并非必须这样做。
timing of eating is important so give
所以进食时间很重要。
yourself 3 hours before bed for no food
睡前3小时不要进食，
hours between dinner and breakfast how
晚餐和早餐之间至少间隔12到14小时。
do we know in the animal studies it
我们如何从动物研究中得知，
caused the um sort of longevity effect
导致寿命延长的不仅仅是卡路里限制呢？ 长寿效应？
it was oh it was the it was so what if I
哦，是的，是的，所以如果我
just restrict my calories instead of
只是限制卡路里摄入而不是
fasting well you can do that uh I met a
禁食呢？嗯，你可以这么做。我遇到一个
guy who was from the calorie restriction
来自卡路里限制
Society there a calorie restriction
协会的人，就是那个卡路里限制
Society yeah which is based on this this
协会，没错，它是基于
research in animals where think about if
动物研究得出的结论：如果
you eat a third less you live a third
你少吃三分之一，寿命就能
longer so for a human that would be 120
延长三分之一。对人类来说，那就是120
years old now I said what do you have
岁。我问他
for breakfast he said well I had five
早餐吃了什么，他说他吃了五
pounds of celery and I'm like okay you
磅芹菜。我说，好吧，你
go do that I'm gonna figure out another
去吃吧，我得想个别的办法。
way so you have to eat enormous amounts
所以你必须吃大量的
of like low calorie food just to feel
低卡路里食物才能有
full right that's why he had all that
饱腹感，对吧？这就是他吃那么多东西的原因，他其实
food so he he was starving and and there
是在挨饿。
are a lot of downsides starving you lose
挨饿有很多弊端，你会失去
muscle which is necessary there's
肌肉，而肌肉是必需的。还会出
certain things that go wrong and so it's
一些问题，所以这
not really the optimal strategy you want
并不是最佳策略。你应该
to do things that mimic starvation so
做一些模拟饥饿的事情。那么，
how do you mimic this period of
如何模拟这种会
starvation that that causes something
引发自噬的饥饿状态呢？
called autophagy which basically means
自噬基本上是指细胞
to eat yourself to basically clean up
吞噬自身来清理
your cell it's like self-cleaning or
细胞。就像…… 自我清洁或
self-repair right and and and so there's
自我修复，对吧？有
a lot of ways to hack that you can do it
很多方法可以增强这种能力，比如
by this longer term overnight fast you
长期隔夜禁食，服用
can do it by certain supplements and and
某些补充剂，以及服用某些
certain medications like rapamycin is
药物，例如雷帕霉素。雷帕霉素
being studied for longevity which is a a
是一种
drug that's used for for cancer and for
用于治疗癌症和
other immune suppressing treatments but
其他免疫抑制疗法的药物，目前正在研究其延寿功效。
it works on this pathway called mtor
它作用于一种名为mTOR的通路，该通路本质上
which essentially is the activation of
是激活
cellular buildup right it causes muscle
细胞构建，对吧？它能促进肌肉
synthesis so if you want to build muscle
合成。所以，如果你想增肌，
you want to activate mtor with protein
你需要用蛋白质激活mTOR，
which is good but you don't want to
这很好，但你不想让它一直处于
activated all the time so this drug
激活状态。这种药物可以
inhibits mtor which is what happens when
抑制mTOR，就像
you starve yourself so what mimics
你挨饿时发生的那样。它模拟
starvation
饥饿状态，从而
and then you get this kind of benefit or
获得这种益处。或者，
drugs like metformin are being studied
二甲双胍等药物也在研究中，
which is another drug that's looking at
它是另一种研究
how do we activate this longevity switch
如何激活
called amk another pathway that's
名为AMK的延寿开关的药物。AMK是
regulating your nutrient sensing so when
调节营养感知的一条通路，当
you have enough you don't have enough
你
nutrients this activates but if we're
营养充足或不足时，这条通路会被激活。但如果我们
running around eating well you can
饮食健康，
actually take this drug and it may have
服用这种药物也可能
an effect there's a large trial going on
有效。 现在正在进行一项大型试验，
now I'm still agnostic about it I I'm
我对此仍然持中立态度，既不
I'm neither Pro or against it I think
赞成也不反对。我认为目前的
the data is not in it for me to start
数据不足以让我
taking it or for my patients to start
或我的病人开始
taking it but it works on some of the
服用它，但它对某些
these sort of uh starvation mimicking
模拟饥饿的“
hacks let's call them so starvation is
捷径”（我们姑且这么称呼它们）确实有效。所以，饥饿
good for us yeah I mean yes I would say
对我们有益？是的，我的意思是，
you have to be careful because you know
你必须小心，因为你知道，有些
people go really to the extreme they go
人会走极端，
like I'm going to not activate mtor
比如他们会说“我不激活mTOR，
because activating mour causes me to age
因为激活mTOR会导致我衰老得
faster and it prevents autophagy and it
更快，它会抑制自噬，还会
builds cancer and it's bad so I'm going
滋生癌细胞，这很糟糕”，然后他们就说“我要
to become a vegan and I'm to eat less
成为素食主义者，我要减少
calories and eventually what happens is
卡路里摄入”，最终的结果是
you lose muscle so it's it's like
你会失去肌肉。所以这就像
Goldilocks you know you need both mtor
金发姑娘的故事一样，你知道，你需要mTOR
activation and mtor ambition you need to
激活和mTOR的“雄心壮志”，你需要
take a breath in you need to take a
呼吸，你需要
breath out you need to be awake you need
清醒，你需要
to go to sleep your heart needs to beat
睡觉，你的心脏需要跳动，你
it needs to relax it's just how the body
需要放松，这就是身体的
works it's a difficult conversation as
运作方式。这是一个很难讨论的话题。
well because of it can provoke
因为它还会引发
disordered eating yeah um various Eating
饮食失调，嗯，各种饮食
Disorders which
失调症，这
are obviously extremely bad in terms of
显然对健康结果非常不利。
health outcom yeah blue zones you
嗯，蓝色地带，你
visited some blue zones haven't you I
去过一些蓝色地带，对吧？我去过。
have what are blue zones and uh what did
什么是蓝色地带？
they teach you about the nature of being
它们教会了你什么关于
healthy well well my friend Dan buner
健康的道理？嗯，我的朋友丹·布纳在
the blue zones after visiting these
参观了
areas in the world where people had
世界上一些
extremely long lives and somebody on the
长寿地区后提出了蓝色地带的概念，有人在
map circled them in blue ink which is
地图上用蓝墨水圈出了这些地区，所以
why they're called Blue
它们被称为蓝色
zones and and uh I visited I iara and
地带。嗯，我去过伊亚拉和
also Sardinia how many of them are there
撒丁岛。有多少个蓝色地带？
uh there's five there's okanawa Japan uh
嗯，有五个，日本的冲绳，加利福尼亚州的
Loma Linda California and uh theoa
洛马琳达，还有哥斯达黎加的西奥亚
peninsula in uh Costa Rica but there are
半岛，但还有
many more I mean I was in turkey and I
很多。我去过土耳其，我
saw Villages where people were very very
看到一些村庄，那里的人们非常非常
old and and so those are the ones that
老。这些是
have been studied how old are we talking
研究过的地区。我们说的年龄是多少？嗯，
well I mean one couple there was like
那里有一对夫妇加起来有
old so they look to be 100 105 109 110 I
岁了，所以他们看起来都100岁或105岁了。  109 110 我
mean Emma Morano was 117 when she died
是说艾玛·莫拉诺去世时117岁，
uh you know
你知道
she and and so so the Cur the question
她，还有，所以，问题
is you know what is different about
是，你知道
these areas and what's different is that
这些地区有什么不同吗？不同之处在于，
you know they're very
你知道，它们非常
isolated and remote so they haven't been
偏远，所以没有受到
our food system they still grow their
我们食品系统现代化带来的负担，他们仍然自己种植
own food I mean I visited this couple he
食物。我是说，我拜访了一对夫妇，他
was I think 90 panotes he was like 97
好像90岁，他97岁，他
his wife was a young
妻子
87 and and they had land and the farm
87岁，他们有土地和
they lived on uh he he was more chill
他们居住的农场。他比较放松，
but she was out there showing us around
但她带我们参观了
all the fruit trees the olive trees the
所有的果树、橄榄树和
garden she planted I mean this massive
她种植的花园。我的意思是，这是一个巨大的
mini farm that she managed herself on
小型农场，她自己管理着，农场位于
the side of a hill when she was running
山坡上，她
up faster than I could get to her at 87
跑得比我快得多，87
years old cooking everything from
岁高龄，所有东西都是她自己做的。
scratch all it wasn't like organic but
虽然不是有机的，但就是有机的，
it was because that's just what they did
因为他们就是这样做的。
they used all heirloom animals like
他们饲养的都是传家宝品种的牲畜，比如
sheep and goats so they had heirloom
绵羊和山羊。所以他们有传家宝品种的
sheep and goat with what's arloom sheep
绵羊和山羊，还有什么是传家宝品种的绵羊？
it's not like some industrialized
有些工业化
hybridized cow that's producing this
杂交奶牛产出的
nasty milk which we shouldn't be
牛奶很糟糕，我们不应该
drinking it's they're having goat milk
喝。他们却在喂羊奶
and goat cheese but their goats are
和做羊奶酪，但他们的山羊
eating wild plants that have
吃的是富含
phytochemical some of those you know
植物化学物质的野生植物。你知道，有些
cheeses and goat milks have actually
奶酪和羊奶的植物
higher phytochemicals even than green
化学物质含量甚至比绿茶还高，绿茶的植物化学物质含量很高，
example cakin that you can get from the
比如，你可以从羊奶中获取很多植物化学物质，而这些羊奶来自那些
are eating the plants that have these
吃富含这些
compounds that benefit their health
有益健康化合物的植物的山羊。
they're also active like um patrao was
它们也很活跃，比如帕特劳，他
like U 95 years old and he was in
95岁了，在
Sardinia and he had to hike five miles a
撒丁岛，他每天要徒步五英里，穿越
day off this extremely Rocky mountainous
极其崎岖的
terrain to hurt his sheep at 95 years
山地去放羊。
old I mean what most 95 years old aren't
我的意思是，大多数95岁的人都不会去
hiking the mountains right he was
爬山吧？他
booming voice stood up straight ice
嗓音洪亮，站得笔直，神采奕奕，一点
clear not hunched over uh funny as heck
也不驼背。呃，真是太有趣了，他还给
sang me a song you know uh and and then
我唱了首歌。你知道，然后你
food uh food that's you know it's rich
知道，它们自然地生活，它们拥有富含植物化学物质的神奇食物。 它
in all these plant compounds that are
富含各种与长寿相关的植物化合物。
example uh in in Korea I was sitting
例如，在韩国，我
with this guy who was making milking the
和一个正在挤
goats and and we're making goat cheese
羊奶的人坐在一起，我们一起做羊奶酪。
together and he like he gives me this
他给了我一
tea I'm like what is this he oh this is
杯茶，我问这是什么，他说这是
Wild Sage Tea and I looked at he said
野生鼠尾草茶。我看了看，他又问这是
what is I said what is the plant I
什么，我说这是什么植物。
looked it up and then I looked up the
我查了一下，
plant and I analyzed you know what it
分析了一下，发现
was and turned out it's it's a extremely
它是一种
phytochemical rich plant that has a lot
富含植物化学物质的植物，其中含有许多与
of these same longevity compounds in it
长寿相关的化合物，
called cakin that know we don't drink a
叫做钙。我们平时不怎么喝
lot of green tea has it you can get from
绿茶，但你可以
from Japan for example and then um you
从日本买到。然后，我们
know uh we we we we just basically see
发现，韩国人
that not only do they have good food
不仅食物健康，而且
they have the the activity um they they
活动量也很大，
have very low levels of stress there was
压力水平很低。
one guy Sylvio I'm I was having dinner
我和西尔维奥一起吃晚饭，
with him he had this mountainous uh kind
他家有一座山，
of that his whole family had had for
他家已经经营了很多
years and they had about 200 sheep and
年了，养了大约200只羊。 他们养
goats and they had a little kind of
山羊，还开了一家小
restaurant they started for people to
餐馆，专门招待客人。
come and so they basically all the
基本上
family cooked and you had everything
全家人都自己做饭，食材都是
farm and I said silia after do I said
农场自产的。我问
silia do you any stress like in your
西莉亚：“你生活中有什么压力吗？”他
life he looked at me like stress like
看着我，好像
like he didn't almost didn't understand
不太理解“压力”这个
the word like you know when things are
词。你知道，就是遇到
difficult and you know hard things are
困难的时候，那种
hard and and get you feel stressed and
感觉很累，压力很大。
he's like oh oh yeah well sometimes at
他恍然大悟地说：“哦，是啊。有时候
night a goat will get out and I'll have
晚上山羊会跑出来，我得去把它抓回来。
it like and sometimes you know when the
还有，
goats are you know giving birth I have
母羊生产的时候，我也得
to go get up early so so they very low
早起。”所以，他们的
levels of stress and then they also have
压力很小。而且，他们还有非常
something which is really important
重要的东西——
which is community so they they have a
社区。他们有
sense of belonging and connection you
归属感和联系感。
know I met Julia who was 100 years old
我遇到过朱莉娅，她100岁了，哦不，是
well sorry 103 months she told me I'm 10
103个月。她告诉我她10岁了，就像
I guess it's like when you're five I'm a
5岁一样。她告诉我她
5 and 3/4 like I'm 103 months you count
5岁零9个月，也就是103个月。
in the months and and she was still
她还在
working she was still making stuff for
工作。 她还在做
weddings and doilies and all things and
婚礼用品、桌布之类的东西，
she didn't have any kids but her niece
她没有孩子，但她的侄女
and her nephew invited her to come stay
和侄子邀请她去他们家住，
with them and so she was living with
所以她就和他们住在一起。
them or another guy Carmine had lost his
另一个人卡迈恩失去了
wife but he was living with family
妻子，但他和家人住在一起，
at ' 86 and animals and sheeps and
在86号经营着一个大花园，养着动物、绵羊和
rabbits so they all part of community
兔子。他们都是社区的一部分，
they have Gatherings they celebrate
他们会聚会，
together there's a sense of belonging
一起庆祝，有一种归属感。
there's no nursing homes there's no
没有养老院，没有
loneliness loneliness is is the new
孤独。孤独真的就像
smoking really I mean we have an
吸烟一样，我的意思是，
epidemic of isolation and loneliness in
在美国，孤独和孤立已经像瘟疫一样
America and increasing around the globe
蔓延，而且这种情况在全球范围内都在加剧。孤独是
and and it's it's it's lethal it's like
致命的，就像
smoking two packs of cigarettes a day
每天抽两包烟一样。
how do we know how do we know that it's
我们怎么知道它很
dangerous yeah there's so much science
危险呢？是的，这方面有很多科学研究，
around this the evidence of of this is
证据非常
is is immense in fact the Surgeon
充分。事实上，
General of America just released a
美国卫生局局长刚刚就此发表了一份
statement about this and an initiative
声明，并提出了一项旨在
to redress loneliness because it's such
消除孤独的倡议，因为孤独
a driver of not just unhappiness but
不仅是造成不快乐的根源，也是
actual disease and death why why are we
疾病的罪魁祸首。 死亡，为什么？为什么我们
so lonely what is it that's happening do
如此孤独？到底发生了什么？
you think it's what is it the internet
你觉得是互联网吗？
or is it oh yeah I mean think about it
还是……哦，对了，想想看，
we used to you know rely on each other
我们过去常常
in communities to to live like like they
在社区里互相依靠，就像他们那样生活。
do for example well I said you know how
比如，我问你，
did it work Sylvia when you have all
西尔维娅，当你养了
these sheep how do you manage it well
这么多羊，你怎么管理？
you know I have like all my friends they
你知道，我的所有朋友都会过来帮忙，到了
come over when it's time for to share
分享
the Sheep they come over and they help
羊的时候，他们就会过来帮忙。
and it's just life is just naturally
生活本来就是自然而然地
connected and you go over to someone's
联系在一起的。你可以去别人
house you walk down the street you you
家，走在街上，坐在
know you sit in the cafe just you have a
咖啡馆里，你有一个
neighborhood you have a family we've
社区，一个家庭。我们
lost that we're all mobile we're all
失去了这些。我们都在
moving around we are all disconnected
四处奔波，我们都
from our families were you know online
与家人失去了联系。
most of the time you know we have face
大部分时间我们都在网上，我们用脸书
we have Facebook instead of actually
代替了
face real face Toof face time I mean
真正的面对面交流。面对面交流当然
it's great to sit here with you in
很好，对吧？通过
person right been the zoom call and it's
Zoom通话，
it's something we've lost and we've
我们失去了这些。
we've lost the value of relationships
我们失去了人际关系的价值
and our culture of achievement and
和我们的文化。 成就和
success and it's just kind of
成功让
disconnected us from what really matters
我们与真正重要的东西——
which is is the human Community is there
人类社群——脱节了。
any way back for that do do you think
你觉得还有挽回的办法吗？
because I was thinking about this the
因为我
other day listen I've talked about this
前几天一直在想这个问题。听着，我已经说过一两次了，
once or twice now but I tried the Vision
但我
Pro the other day oh you did yeah yeah
前几天试用了Vision Pro。哦，你试用了，是啊是啊是啊。嗯，就
um incredible in terms of the technology
技术而言，它确实很棒。但从
potential implications over the long
长远来看，它的潜在影响却令人担忧。
term yeah you're just going to wear that
你会一直戴着它，完全
all the time and forget about every
忘记一切。它的确很
exactly and it was it was incredible
神奇，
like the fact that I can I can just sit
我可以坐在
there and just the things I do with my
那里，我放在
hands that are on my lap impact all of
腿上的手所做的任何操作都会影响到
these massive screens in front of me you
我面前的这些巨大屏幕。你
can see when again when you play it
可以想象，随着时间的推移，
forward that this is going to get
它的价格会越来越
cheaper and cheaper and cheaper and
低，越来越便宜，越来越
cheaper more accessible the apps going
普及，应用程序也会越来越
to get better and then we think about
好。然后我们想想，
what that's going to mean for loneliness
这对孤独意味着什么？
yeah when I could go hang out you know
当我可以
with my friends in a virtual world and
在虚拟世界里和朋友们一起玩，同时
do my work in a virtual world and date
还能工作的时候。 虚拟世界，在
in a virtual world watch pornography in
虚拟世界里约会，在虚拟世界里看色情片
a virtual world and all of these things
等等，
no I still like hugging and holding
不，我仍然喜欢拥抱和
hands how do you do
牵手，在虚拟世界里怎么可能做到呢？
hope like are you hopeful for us being
你希望我们
able to turn around the loneliness and
能够扭转孤独和
isolation epidemic I mean it's a tough
隔离的蔓延吗？我的意思是，这确实是个难题。
one I think we have to you know rethink
我认为我们必须重新思考
how we live and what we do and the
我们的生活方式、我们的所作所为以及
communities we build and I think there
我们建立的社区。我认为这方面的
efforts of that happening all around so
努力正在世界各地进行。所以，在
just at the same time we're seeing this
我们看到
epidemic of loneliness we're also seeing
孤独蔓延的同时，我们也看到了
you know a lot of initiatives of
很多旨在
community building and connection and
建设社区、建立联系和增强
belonging and so there's a lot of these
归属感的举措。
communities that I'm involved with that
我参与了很多这样的社区活动，
are happening and and you know I'm on
而且我还在一个
the board of something called the belong
名为“归属
Center which is really about addressing
中心”（Belong Center）的机构的董事会任职，该机构致力于解决
loneliness and creating ways and
孤独问题，并创造
mechanisms for people to connect and be
人们实时联系和相处的方式和机制。
with each other in real time I think it
我认为这
needs to be a systemic thing I think a
需要系统性地解决。我认为，对于
lot with a lot of the issues we've
我们
talked about relating to longevity and
讨论过的很多与长寿和
diet the best answers are probably going
饮食相关的问题，最好的答案可能都是真正
to be the really TR truly systemic ones
系统性的。
that come from how we designed societies
这源于我们如何设计社会，
yeah like regulation and policy and how
比如规章制度、政策，以及
we designed cities and green spaces and
我们如何设计城市、绿地、
libraries and community community
图书馆、社区
centers and all these kinds of things
中心等等。是的，这似乎……
yeah that seems to you know I I did a um
你知道，我
I realized this was a problem a long
很久以前就意识到这是一个问题。
earthquake and I I went helping there
地震后我去了海地，当时那里还是一片灾难，我是最早抵达
first Medical Teams on the ground and uh
现场的医疗队之一。
in that process I met Paul Farmer who
在那段时间里，我遇到了保罗·法默，他
was an incredible Visionary doctor from
是一位来自
har Harvard who went to Haiti and helped
哈佛大学的杰出的、富有远见的医生。他去了海地，
solve the problem of TB and AIDS by
通过建立社区卫生工作者队伍，帮助解决了结核病和艾滋病的问题。
then went on to build a network of
之后，他又建立了一个遍布全球的
community health workers of over 11,000
社区卫生工作者网络，拥有超过11000名成员。这个网络
globally it was a model for the Clinton
成为了克林顿基金会
and Gates Foundation and what he
和盖茨基金会的典范。他
realized was that we didn't didn't have
意识到，我们并不缺乏
a lack of the right science or the right
正确的科学或
medicines to heal these problems we we
药物来治愈这些问题——我们
know what to do with TB andas it was it
知道如何治疗结核病——问题在于
was you know a lack of people being able
人们缺乏
to do the basic things that they needed
基本的生活必需品，
to do like get clean water or have a
比如获得干净的水，或者拥有一块
watch know what time it was and so he
手表来知道时间。因此，他
built this network of community health
建立了这个网络。 我接触了一些社区卫生
workers and realized that Community was
工作者，意识到社区就是
medicine and so he he was their
良药，社区就是他们的
neighbors and so I I came back from that
邻居。
very moved and I realized that chronic
我深受触动，意识到
disease was also an issue that that
慢性病也是一个问题。
chronic disease was wasn't wasn't
慢性病本身并不具有
infectious but it was contagious right
传染性，但它确实会“传染”。
you're more likely to be overweight if
如果
your friends overweight than if your
你的朋友超重，你超重的可能性比你的
family members are overweight right that
家人超重的可能性更大。
your social networks are more important
社交网络
than your genetic work networks in
比基因网络更能
determining your health right you're
决定你的健康。
you're basically you look around at your
基本上，看看你最
five closest friends it's probably kind
亲密的五个朋友，
of the way you are too right and and so
你很可能也会变成那样。所以
I realized that we needed to use the
我意识到，我们需要利用
power of community to transform our
社区的力量来改变我们的
health and our behavior and and and I
健康和行为。我
can tell you what to eat and what to do
可以告诉你该吃什么、该做什么，
but if all your friends are doing the
但如果你的所有朋友都
opposite it's going to be hard right so
反其道而行之，那就很难奏效。所以
I I created a program with Rick Warren
我与里克·沃伦（Rick Warren）共同创建了一个
called The Daniel Plan faith-based
名为“但以理计划”（The Daniel Plan）的信仰型
wellness program where we got 15,000
健康计划。
people to sign up in the first week at
在第一周，我们就吸引了15000人注册，
first year we created a book called The
第一年就帮助大家减掉了25万磅的体重。我们还出版了一本书，名为《
Daniel Plan of how to do this in
但以理计划》，讲述了如何在社区中实施这项计划。
the five FS for for getting healthy
五个“F”代表健康，分别
right it's Faith
是信仰（Faith）、
Friends food Fitness and focus which is
朋友（Friends）、食物（Food）、健身（Fitness）和专注（Focus），也就是
your mindset so and and it was amazingly
你的心态。这个方法非常
effective we scaled it to thousand
有效，我们把它推广到
churches around the world and and it
世界各地上千个教堂，它
really was helping people in small
确实帮助人们以小组形式
groups do this together so there there
一起实践。当时
was no health coach there was no
没有健康教练，也没有
nutritionist it was just you know me and
营养师，只有我和
another doctor and we basically created
另一位医生。我们创建了
this program which could be delivered in
这个课程，让
a curriculum that people did in small
人们可以在
groups together and this Saddleback
小组中一起学习。
Church with Rick Warren had an
瑞克·沃伦牧师所在的马鞍峰教会（Saddleback Church）
infrastructure already of groups meeting
已经有一个每周聚会的团体组织，
every week so we just hijacked that and
所以我们利用了这个组织，把
put the curriculum in there and people
课程放进去，人们就开始学习，效果非常
did it and and it was really powerful
好。
and we've seen that now at Cleveland
现在我在克利夫兰诊所也看到了这一点，我们在
with with groups there as well that lost
那里也和一些失去信仰的团体一起实践了这个方法。专注（
F Focus do you is that an umbrella word
Focus）这个词是否也涵盖了目标（Purpose）、
also for purpose purpose meaning and
意义（Mean）和
purpose Yeah Yeah from reading your work
目的（Many）。是的，读了你的作品后，
I I came to learn that purpose is a sort
我了解到目标是一种
of longevity Factor
长寿因素，而且是
100% to what extent I mean the data is
百分之百的。我的意思是，数据
really clear I was a recent paper in
非常清楚地表明，最近发表在《美国医学会杂志》（Journal of the American Medical Association）上的一篇论文
Association showed that those who had
显示，那些拥有
meaning and purpose lived seven years
意义和目标的人寿命比其他人
longer and what do they mean by meaning
长七年。 他们所说的意义
and purpose in that context it's
和目的，在这个语境下指的是
whatever your meaning and purpose is it
任何意义和目的。它
could be you want to be there for your
可以是你想陪伴你的
grandchild it could be you're a
孙辈，可以是你想成为一名
scientist and want to make a discovery
科学家并做出新的发现，也
it could be that you you're a novelist
可以是你是一位小说家，
you want to write your next novel or
想创作你的下一部小说。当然，它不一定是
it's not a job necessarily it's not no
工作，也不一定非得是工作。
it doesn't have to be I mean for me you
对我来说，
know my purpose is ending needless
我的目标是
through the power of this new thinking
通过这种新的思维方式
and model and and the new company that I
和模式的力量，为数百万人终结不必要的痛苦。我
co-founded function health is I think
联合创立的新公司 Function Health，我认为是能够
able to do that at scale by empowering
大规模实现这一目标的先锋，它通过赋予
people with their own Health Data giving
人们自己的健康数据，为
them an AI co-pilot to uplevel their
他们提供人工智能助手来提升
health and to help them understand
健康水平，并帮助他们实时了解自身健康
what's going on in real time and to me
状况。对我而言，
building that creating that scaling that
构建、创造、扩展，
getting people access to things that are
让人们获得那些
not happening in your doctor's office or
在医生办公室、医疗
your Healthcare System not happening in
保健系统或
your annual physical you're not getting
年度体检中难以获得的资源，让他们无法获得
the latest science and medicine so how
最新的科学和医学信息，这才是关键所在。那么，
do we accelerate that change so for me
我们该如何加速这种改变呢？对我来说，这就是关键所在。
that that that drives me every day gets
每天早上，这种动力都激励​​着我，让我
me excited to wake up and I'm very
兴奋地醒来。我
passionate but of course you know I'm
充满热情，当然，你也知道，我
also passionate about my friends and my
对我的朋友和
community I'm passionate about my health
社区充满热情，我对我的健康充满热情，
I'm passionate about having fun you know
我对享受生活充满热情，比如
like and doing things that I love so I
做我喜欢的事情。所以我
think you know it's really important to
认为，
design your life and in terms of your
规划你的人生非常重要，就你的
values what do you care about what
价值观而言，你关心什么？什么
matters to you what makes you come alive
对你来说重要？什么让你充满活力？
what gives you energy what takes away
什么给你能量？什么会消耗
your energy and and focus on those
你的能量？专注于那些能带
things that that take you to where you
你到达你想去的地方的事情。
want to go why would not having a
为什么没有
purpose make us die earlier I mean you
目标会让我们过早离世呢？
see it all the time Stephen I mean you
我的意思是，斯蒂芬，你经常看到这种情况。你看，
look at you know people retire literally
人们
in the retirement age here is 65 which
在退休年龄就退休了，退休年龄是65岁，
I'm going to be this year which is a
我今年就要退休了，
little scary to say
说起来有点可怕，
that you know I'm just getting started
你知道，我才刚刚开始。
and uh people think well you know if you
人们会想，如果你
look at people who retire the the death
看看退休的人，他们的死亡率似乎很高，
retire die die like they there's a much
退休的人好像很快就死了，他们的
higher death rate if if for example
死亡率要高得多。比如说，如果
you're married and your spouse dies and
你已婚，你的配偶去世了，
you've been together your life whole
你们相伴一生。
life you're likely to die very quickly
你很可能在那之后很快就会死，
after that is this STS to support that
STS 100% 支持这一点吗？
100% 100% that's crazy
100% 支持？太疯狂了。是啊，
yeah why what happens you know wonder
为什么会发生这种情况？你知道吗？
you stop moving you get depressed yeah
你会停止行动，你会抑郁，你会
you get depressed you stop moving I I
抑郁，你会停止行动。我
had a patient who the most beautiful
有一个病人，他拥有最美好的
relationship I I I it was such a deep
爱情，
love and they were together for like 40
他们在一起大约 40
years and his wife got breast cancer and
年，他们的爱非常深厚。他的妻子得了乳腺癌，最终去世了。
she just didn't make it and when he died
他去世的时候，
and he was healthy guy he was fit
他身体很健康，
healthy ate well he went into heart
饮食也很健康，但他却出现了
failure like literally heart failure his
心力衰竭，真的是心力衰竭，他的
heart couldn't pump and he he had a true
心脏无法泵血。他确实患有某种
medical condition that showed up on
疾病，
scans and imaging he was in trouble and
扫描和影像检查都显示出来，情况很糟糕。
I was like wow you know I looked it up
我当时就想，哇，你知道吗？我查阅了相关资料，发现
and and there's actually evidence for
确实有证据表明，
emotional shock and loss heartbreak
情绪冲击和失落感会
caused his heart to literally break
导致心力衰竭，他的心脏真的会破裂，
physically not just emotionally and we
不仅仅是情绪上的。我们
were able to get him back and fix it by
通过
dealing with that emotional heartbreak
处理这种情绪上的心碎，
and by using energy healing and a lot of
运用能量疗法以及许多
other things with him that that helped
其他方法，帮助
him overcome it but that's when I was
他恢复了健康，克服了困难。但那时我
like wow you know the mind you know
就想，哇，你知道，人的思想，你知道，
listen even the biggest and most
即使是最强大的人，
powerful Pharmacy in the world is
世界上最强大的药房就在
between your ears you know and it can do
你的脑子里，你知道吗？它能做到
all kinds of stuff trauma yeah does
很多事情，创伤，没错，
trauma play a role in all longev 100% I
创伤在所有人的寿命中都扮演着重要角色，百分之百。我的
mean you know um it's it's amazing how
意思是，你知道吗？令人惊讶的是，
in medical school we just did not learn
我们在医学院竟然没有学到
this but there there there's such a link
这一点，但
between trauma and everything in your
创伤确实与你
life but particularly disease there's a
生活中的一切，尤其是疾病，有着千丝万缕的联系。
questionnaire we use called the ace
我们使用一种叫做ACE
questionnaire adverse childhood
问卷（童年逆境
events and it basically ask you a series
经历问卷）的调查问卷，它会问你一系列
of questions you can look it up online
问题。你可以在网上找到它，也
you can link to it in your show notes
可以把它链接到你的节目笔记里，
it's free and it says well were your
它是免费的。它会问你：你的
parents divorce was there alcoholism in
父母是否离婚？
your family did your parents fight in
你的家庭中是否有酗酒者？你的父母是否在
front of you did anybody hit you were
你面前吵架？是否有人打过你？
you sexually abused and he just goes
你是否遭受过性虐待？它会列出一长串问题，比如你的
through this whole list there any family
家庭
members in prison you know and and the
成员是否入狱等等。
higher your
你的
score the more likely you are to have
得分越高，你患上
health issues be obese have autoimmune
健康问题、肥胖、自身免疫性
disease get cancer get heart disease get
疾病、癌症、心脏病和
diabetes it's really striking and so
糖尿病的可能性就越大。这真的很惊人。所以，
trauma is registered in your body and
创伤会在你的身体里留下痕迹。
there's a book called the body keeps
有一本书叫做《身体记忆》（The Body Keeps Score），
score and Carolyn mace was a sort of a
卡罗琳·梅斯（Carolyn Mace）是一位
Mystic said you your biography becomes
神秘主义者，她说…… 你的经历会变成
your biology and it works the other way
你的生物学，反之亦然。
too from up down right your biology can
从上到下，你的生物学也会
become your bi graphy if you're eating
变成你的经历。如果你饮食
crap and you're nutritionally deficient
不健康，营养不良，
and you have all these health issues and
并且患有各种健康问题，比如
mercury poisoning well that can kind of
汞中毒，这些都会
affect your mental health too in your
影响你的心理健康。
story but but we know really clearly
我们非常清楚地知道，
that your trauma is influencing your
你的创伤会影响你的
biology and so we have to we have to
生物学，因此我们必须
deal with this in medicine whether it's
在医学上解决这个问题，无论是
depression or whether it's autoimmune
抑郁症、自身免疫性
diseases or whether it's other health
疾病还是其他健康
issues and we now have an incredible
问题。现在，迷幻药领域正在发生一场惊人的
revolution in psychedelics which is for
革命，它
the first time showing us that we have
首次向我们展示了治疗创伤后应激障碍（
treatments for things like PTSD which
PTSD）等疾病的方法。PTSD 以前
really were very hard to treat you can
很难治疗，你可以
give people a sedative you know but that
给病人服用镇静剂，但仅此而已，
was it maybe some therapy which barely
或许还可以进行一些效果甚微的治疗。
worked if that but you you start to work
但现在，我们开始使用
with these these compounds that change
这些能够改变
the structure and function of the brain
大脑结构和功能的化合物，
which is really amazing to me it's not
这对我来说真的很神奇。它
just uh like a normal drug where you
不像普通的药物，你
take the drug and you have to keep
服用后就必须持续
taking it men you took OIC once and you
服用。你服用一次阿片类药物（OIC）
would stay losing weight forever right
就会一直减肥，对吧？
it's like taking these psychedelics you
它就像…… 这些迷幻剂你服用
it once or twice and it changes your
一两次就能改变你
physiological functioning in your brain
大脑的生理
response it changes compounds in your
反应，改变大脑中的化合物，
brain like bdnf that grow new brain
比如脑源性神经营养因子（BDNF），它能促进新的脑
connections and repair and heal things
连接生长，修复和治愈
in your brain and so we're seeing new
大脑损伤。所以我们看到了应对
ways to deal with trauma that I I feel
创伤的新方法，这让我感到
really exciting and Maps is an
非常兴奋。迷幻剂研究协会（MAPS）是一个
organization um The multi-disciplinary
组织，它是一个多学科的迷幻剂研究
Association of psychedelic studies you
协会，你
can share that link but it's it's
可以分享一下链接，它
sharing all the research about treating
分享所有关于治疗
depression anxiety trauma responses PTSD
抑郁症、焦虑症、创伤反应、创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）和
relational issues what you think of
人际关系问题的研究。你对
psychedelics have you tried them yes I
迷幻剂有什么看法？你试过吗？是的，我试过。
have which ones have you tried
你试过哪些？你
you know all of them which ones haven't
知道，所有你试过的吗？哪些你没试过？嗯，
you tried um I haven't tried Iain oh
我没试过。伊恩，哦，好的。是的，
okay yeah it's quite strong adct for
它很容易
addiction right yeah um but you know I
上瘾，对吧？嗯，但是你知道，我是
grew up in the 70s so uh mushrooms were
在70年代长大的，所以蘑菇是
psychedelic mushrooms were big part of
迷幻剂，蘑菇是我
my my Awakening uh and and my personal
觉醒和个人
Journey tried LSD I've tried peyote I've
旅程的重要组成部分。我试过LSD，试过佩奥特仙人掌，试过岩
tried iwasa I've tried bufo I've tried
沙仙人掌，试过蟾蜍毒素，我试过
pretty much all of them because I just
很多。 几乎所有这些，因为我本身就是个
sort of an adventurer in my biology and
生物学和
and my mind and I can tell you that they
思想上的冒险家，我可以告诉你，它们
really helped me uh which one helped you
真的帮了我很多。嗯，哪个对你帮助
the most and and give me a a story of
最大？给我讲讲它是
how it helped you my girlfriend's
如何帮助你的。我女朋友
actually in uh in Costa Rica right now
现在在哥斯达黎加为
serving iasa and I spent a year and a
IASA工作，我花了一年半的时间
half um investing in and we took a um
投资了一家
psychedelics company public called the
名为
tie Life Sciences so I work in
TIE Life Sciences的迷幻药公司，并把它推向了市场。我
partnership with maps and Compass
与Maps和Compass
Pathways we at a tie we invest Inc
Pathways合作，我们TIE投资公司就是
Compass Pathways which is so I'm quite
Compass Pathways，所以我投入了很多。
heavily oh you're very into that yeah
哦，你很热衷于此啊。是的，是的，是的。我
yeah yeah i' yeah spent about a year as
花了大约一年半的时间
a year and a about a year as the
担任
creative director of the company purely
这家公司的创意总监，纯粹是
because I I just was interested so I
因为我对此感兴趣。我
invested about seven figures in the
投资了大约七位数，
business then I joined as a creative
然后以创意
director to stay close and then I my my
总监的身份加入，以便保持密切联系。我的
contract was basically to leave on the
合同基本上是在
day of the IPO so it ipoed on the NASDAQ
IPO当天离开，所以它在纳斯达克上市，市值
3.4 billion and I left the next day
34亿美元，我第二天就离开了。是的，很
basically yeah amazing but it was so
神奇，但那只是
just it was because I was interested in
因为我……
mental health I heard about this
我对心理健康很感兴趣，我听说过
epidemic of Mental Health no good
心理健康危机，而且没有好的
answers yeah and psychedelics and the
解决办法。迷幻药以及
around things like
围绕着诸如赛
cybin which is the active compound of
宾（Cybin，神奇蘑菇的活性成分）之类的药物进行的临床研究真的很
interesting and I I didn't need to work
有意思。我当时不用工作，
so I just it's fascinating I mean you
所以就沉迷其中。你
know there was this uh recently heard a
知道吗，我最近听了
presentation by a Stanford scientist
一位斯坦福大学科学家的演讲，他正在
who's studying ibigan for trauma
研究伊比甘（Ibigan）对创伤、
depression anxiety but addiction and
抑郁、焦虑和成瘾的疗效，这
it's quite interesting it's a compound
很有意思。伊比甘是从西非一种
that you take from a bark of a tree from
树的树皮中提取的化合物，
West Africa the batry and it somehow
它似乎可以
shuts off the withdrawal so we know
阻止戒断反应。我们从
medically that when you stop narcotics
医学上知道，当你停止服用麻醉剂时，
you go through physiological withdrawal
你会经历生理戒断反应，
which is a medical phenomena it just
这是一种医学现象。伊比甘似乎可以阻止这种反应，就像
stops that somehow it's like a one dose
服用一次就能阻止一样。当然，
stay for a long time nor Iain that may
伊比甘也有一些代谢物会长时间停留在体内，它们可能会
mitigate those effects and block those
减轻这些影响并阻断某些
receptors and we don't really quite
受体。我们目前还没有完全
understand it yet but I did I did have a
了解其中的机制。但我确实有一个
thought which is that when you look at
想法，那就是当你查看
the Yale food addiction scale which is a
耶鲁食物成瘾量表（Yale Food Addiction scale）时，这是一个经过
validated metric for food addiction now
验证的食物成瘾评估工具。
different people have various degrees
不同的人有不同的程度，对吧？ 有些人
right there are people who can't stop
总是忍不住
eating sheet cakes and there's people
吃蛋糕，有些人偶尔会
who you know crave ice cream once in a
想吃冰淇淋，
while it's not true food addiction but
这虽然不是真正的食物成瘾，但
you look at the data globally 14% of
看看全球数据，就会发现14%的
adults and 12% of kids meet the criteria
成年人和12%的儿童符合
according to the Yale food addiction
耶鲁食物成瘾
scale for food addiction from Ultra
量表对超
processed food from sugar carb refined
加工食品（糖、碳水化合物和精制
carbohydrates so I I actually talked to
碳水化合物）的成瘾标准。所以我跟
one of the leading Ryan researchers I
瑞安研究所的一位首席研究员聊过，我
said wouldn't it be interesting to do a
说，如果做一个
pilot where we took people who had food
试点项目，让一些有食物成瘾的人服用伊比甘（Ibigian），
we saw what happened I mean it could be
看看会发生什么，岂不是很有意思？我
think there will be a nor ibigan which
觉得这可能很有意思，或许能抑制这种成瘾。而且我认为，伊比甘的
is a metabolite of ibigan that I think
代谢产物——去甲伊比甘（Nor Ibigian）——
may be doing a lot of the effect that's
可能发挥了很大作用，它
something you can take on a daily basis
可以
instead of OIC for example what I heard
代替阿片类药物（OIC）每天服用。我听说
about Iain is that the side effects are
伊比甘的副作用相当
quite yeah it can be quite significant
严重，
but it's it's the main side effect is is
但它的主要副作用是
a heart side effect it increases
心脏方面的，它会延长
something called the QT and interval
QT间期，这可能会导致心脏骤停。
which can put you into an arhythmia
心律失常，
which can a fatal heart rhythm um and
这可能会导致致命的心律失常，
you'll have to be monitored when you're
服用期间需要密切监测。
taking it but we found it if you take uh
但我们发现，如果服用
High higher Doses and even IV magnesium
高剂量，甚至静脉注射镁（
which is actually what we use in the
实际上，我们在
emergency room to treat arhythmia like
急诊室就是用这种方法治疗心律失常的，比如
if your heart's beating like crazy and
心脏狂跳不止，
you're going to die we give you
濒临死亡时，我们会在万不得已的情况下才给你静脉
intervenous magnesium as the last resort
注射镁），都可能导致心律失常。
well you can pre-treat with magnesium
当然，你也可以预先服用镁，
and that stops that phenomena so there's
这样就能阻止这种现象。所以有
a lot of ways to deal with it but I do
很多方法可以应对这种情况。但我确实
think we're in a psychedelic era and uh
认为我们正处于一个迷幻药时代，
it's really hard to me because I think
这对我来说真的很难，因为我觉得
there's so many problems as a doctor I
作为一名医生，有很多问题我
can't solve you know if someone has a
无法解决。比如，如果有人有
health issue but their trauma is
健康问题，但他们的创伤却
controlling their
控制着他们的
behavior and unless they deal with the
行为，除非他们处理好
trauma it's hard to address the things
创伤，否则很难解决
that they need to do to fix their
他们需要做的事情来改变
behavior in their life right so if
他们生活中的行为。所以，如果
you're if you're you're traumatized
你因为
abuse when you were a kid you know and
小时候被强奸或遭受性虐待而受到创伤，你知道，
I've had my own trauma I had incest when
我自己也有过创伤。
I was a kid I had you know kind of a
我小时候经历过乱伦，我的
rough K childhood in many ways incest
童年很坎坷，在很多方面都是如此。
when you were a kid yeah yeah so I've
所以，我
had to deal with this myself and doing
不得不自己面对这件事，而
that has really helped me to kind of
这真的帮助我
recover and repair my own emotional
恢复和修复了我的情感
architecture and have a really a sense
结构，并让我拥有了
have before did you have symptoms of
以前从未有过的安全感。你在
that trauma in in your early life or
早年或
your adult life 100% um you I was highly
成年生活中出现过这种创伤的症状吗？百分之百有。嗯，我当然很
functional obviously I mean I'm doctor
能干，我是医生，
I've written many books done a lot in
写了很多书，在
the world but it was really affecting my
世界上做了很多事情，但这确实影响了我的
um way of being in relationships and
人际关系和
your sexual health or your in your sort
性健康，或者说，
of not my Sexual Health but more my
不仅仅是性健康，更多的是我的
romantic relationships and even
恋爱关系，甚至
sometimes work relationships where I I
有时影响到工作关系，我
really developed a a pattern and my it
形成了一种模式。我的
was also trauma that I had from my
创伤也来自我的
mother who was a wonderful woman but she
母亲，她是一位很棒的女性，但她的父母都是
was a child of deaf parents so she had
聋哑人，所以她不得不承担起父母的责任，
to become their parent and she basically
她基本上
was a what you call a parentified child
是一个被“父母化”的孩子，她是
and she was the adult so she never had a
成年人，所以她从未有过
childhood and then she did the same
童年。然后她也
thing to me she made me her therapist
对我做了同样的事情，她让我成为她的心理治疗师，
because she was depressed and in bad
因为她很抑郁，情况很糟糕。 她
marriages and chose men who were broken
选择和那些内心破碎的男人结婚，因为
CU she thought love was taking care of
她认为爱就是照顾那些
broken people and so I developed this
破碎的人。所以我
emptiness in my heart and I couldn't
内心深处感觉像被掏空了一样，无法
really overcome that and so I did a lot
摆脱这种空虚感。于是我做了很多
of work did medicine Journeys I did lot
功课，尝试了各种疗愈方法，最终
able to really break through and release
突破了困境，释放了内心的创伤。
that and when I did it was like it was
当我做到这一点时，感觉就像是
literally the programming changed you
程序彻底改变了。你
know you got little voice in your head
知道，你脑子里一直有个声音，
all the time some has a very annoying
有些人脑子里有个很烦人的
voice in your head and it just says
声音，它总是说
stuff all the time that you know you
一些你希望它
just wish it wouldn't or it it dictates
不要说的话，或者它会以
your behavior in certain ways that you
你不希望的方式支配你的行为。
wish it wouldn't oh I I never thought
哦，我以前从没想过
this was possible but literally that
这会成为现实，但那个
voice changed and what it said changed
声音真的改变了，它说的话改变了，
and how it was in relationships changed
它在人际关系中的表现也改变了，
and it was physiologically different and
生理上也发生了变化。
I didn't have that sense of trauma and I
我不再有那种创伤感了。我
had another friend who had the same
还有一个朋友也有同样的经历，
thing and he had you know a mother who
他的母亲
was a yeller and a screamer and and was
是个爱吼叫、爱尖叫的人，给他造成了很大的心理创伤。他
traumatizing couldn't tell the truth and
不敢说真话，也
wasn't honest because he was afraid he
不敢诚实，因为他害怕遭到母亲的
was going to get attack packed and hurt
攻击。 他很受伤，
and so he was that little boy and so
所以他就是那个小男孩，他
this part of his brain that wasn't
大脑的某个部分出了问题。
working and we we helped him get MDMA
我们帮助他接受了MDMA
therapy uh which is you know MDMA is a
治疗，MDMA是一种
compound that that isn't like a
化合物，它不是
psychedelic but it has effects on PTSD
迷幻剂，但对创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）有疗效。
and he said as like that part of his
他说，就像他
brain just turned off and he stopped
大脑的那个部分突然关闭了一样，他不再
having that feeling and he was able to
有那种感觉，他能够
tell the truth and speak what he felt
说出真相，表达自己的感受。
and you know was powerful and the
你知道，这很有效。
symptoms that you experienced in your
你后来在人际关系方面经历的症状是什么？是不是
that just like a bit struggling to find
有点难以建立亲密关系？你知道，我
form attachments uh you know I had what
属于
was called an anxious attachment style
焦虑型依恋。
so um basically uh I I was anxious about
基本上，我对
the relationship and wouldn't be honest
恋爱关系感到焦虑，不会坦诚地表达自己的
with how I felt or what I was doing and
感受或行为。
it wasn't like I was lying like I'm
我不是在撒谎，而是有所
lying but Omission or if I if I say how
隐瞒。如果我说出
I'm feeling or what I want then they're
我的感受或想法，他们就会
going to leave me or they're going to
离开我，或者
they're going to be gone and so I
他们会消失。所以我内心出现了一个
developed this this hole in this
空洞，
emptiness that affected my relationships
影响了我的人际关系，情况很
and and and it was bad you know like so
糟糕。
if if my partner for example I'm just
比如说，如果我的伴侣，
this partner she she was a perfectionist
她是个完美主义者，
and she really had a hard time opening
很难敞开心扉，
up and she had an avoiding attachment
而且她有回避型依恋
style so like one time I had seen her in
模式。有一次，我
three weeks and she didn't really want
三个星期没见到她了，她根本不想和我
to connect or hug or be together and and
交流，不想拥抱，也不想和我待在一起。她说：“
she's like I need to get used to you and
我需要习惯你。”
I'm like and so I I just could feel this
我当时就感觉到了那种
like visceral reaction of panic and fear
本能的恐慌、恐惧
and hurt and like now I don't have any
和伤害。现在我没有这些感觉了。你
of that you know what was it that you
知道吗？你
did that fixed it do your do your work
做了什么才解决了这个问题？
earlier your life is going to be
早点开始努力吧。你的生活会很
difficult I think I wish you know it's
艰难。我想，我希望你知道，这就像
like it's like when I was sick with
我以前得
chronic illness and I was had chronic
慢性病的时候一样，
fatigue syndrome and I had mold issues
我患有慢性疲劳综合征、霉菌感染
and lime disease and I was so sick you
和莱姆病，我病得很重。你
I didn't have a path you know I I I
知道，我没有方向，没有路，我
didn't know what to do and so I was
不知道该怎么办，就像
groping in the dark and finding a crumb
在黑暗中摸索，找到一点线索。
here and a crumb there and I talk to
这里一点，那里一点，我跟
this person and that person I would P
这个人、那个人交谈，我像P
Peach to get patch together this whole
Peach一样拼凑出这套
approach that finally allowed me to get
最终让我康复的方法。
well and I wish I'd known now what I
我真希望我当时就知道我现在所
knew then it would have been better in
知道的一切，那样的话，我康复的时间就不会像现在这样长达
the year not 10 years that it took me to
十年，甚至可能更
get better or maybe even shorter and if
短。如果
IID done the work on myself when I was
我在20岁、30岁的时候就开始自我疗愈，
20 and 30 and not waited till I was 50
而不是等到50岁、
and 60 I would have you know not
60岁，我就能
prevented a lot of suffering and so my
避免很多痛苦。所以，我的
my advice to people is to if you are
建议是，如果你正在
struggling with any of these relational
与这些人际关系
issues with yourself there's work to be
问题作斗争，那就说明还有很多事情要做。有很多
done there's great amazing paths out
很棒的方法可以
there to help look at things like Byron
帮助你审视自己，比如拜伦·
Katie's you know work called the work
凯蒂的“功课”（The Work），这
which is a way of looking at your own
是一种审视自己
thoughts and your own your own
想法和
perspective there's so many things that
视角的方法。
you can do psychedelic medicine MDMA
你可以尝试很多方法，比如迷幻药、MDMA
assistant therapy psilocybon assistant
辅助疗法、裸盖菇素辅助
therapy it's coming it's not available
疗法等等。这些疗法正在发展，虽然目前还不是
to everybody yet but it's coming fast I
人人都能获得，但它们正在快速发展。我
think maybe even this year the MDA
认为MDMA
assisted therapy will be FDA approved so
辅助疗法可能今年就会普及。  FDA批准了，所以
I feel like you know everybody's on
我觉得你知道，每个人都在走
their own Journey but you don't have to
自己的路，但你不必
stay stuck in the biologic iCal or
一直困在
psychological framework that you are now
你现在的生物或心理框架里。无论
like there is a way to heal at any time
何时，都有治愈的方法，对吧？
right whether you're 65 or 25 I think
无论你是65岁还是25岁。我认为
this isessential to the concern a lot of
这对很多
people have but also the resistance is
人来说至关重要，但阻力也在于，
we kind of see ourselves as being fixed
我们似乎认为自己是固定的，
especially the older you get you kind of
尤其年纪越大，就越会
assume both our health our motivation
认为自己的健康、动力、创伤、思想等等，都成了“
this who I am this is who I am now I can
我是谁，我现在是谁”。我也许可以
maybe act differently or whatever I can
改变自己的行为，或者
learn tips and tricks to like I don't
学习一些技巧，比如
know become better at sales or speaking
提高销售或演讲能力，
but fundamentally my is my
但从根本上说，我的那些废话就是我的
it is me yeah exactly and that
废话，它们就是我。没错，正是这种想法束缚着
holds us kind of imprisons us yeah so my
我们，囚禁着我们。所以我
my message is number one we now have the
想说的是，第一，我们现在拥有
science and technology and medicine to
科学、技术和医学手段来
upgrade your biological software and
升级你的生物软件，
reverse chronic disease reverse your
逆转慢性疾病，逆转你的
biological age my biological age is 43
生物年龄。我的生物年龄是43岁，
even though I'm
尽管我已经
65 how do they know your biological age
65岁了。他们怎么知道你的生物年龄呢？哦，这是
oh well it's a kind of fancy technology
一种很先进的技术，它通过
that looks at something called The epig
观察一些叫做……的东西来判断。 表观
genome which is the above your genome
基因组位于你的基因组之上，是
the regulator of your gene expression
基因表达的调节器，它会
which changes based on different insults
根据
and things in your life whether it's
你生活中的各种刺激和因素而改变，比如
diet toxins lifestyle so we can measure
饮食、毒素和生活方式。现在我们可以测量
that now so that's what it was uh so you
它了。所以，你
can upgrade your biological software and
可以升级你的生物软件，也
you can upgrade your psycho emotional
可以升级你的心理、情感和
spiritual software it's really possible
精神软件。这完全可行，
and I've seen it happen and I've seen it
而且我亲眼见过，
happen with many people I think the
很多人都做到了。我认为
Psychedelic Revolution is probably like
迷幻药革命可能就像是
OIC for mental health you know but with
心理健康领域的阿片类药物革命，只不过
a lot of side effects I mean that
副作用比较多。我的意思是，
safety profile for these compounds
这些化合物的安全性非常高，
they're really really safe
它们非常安全，
and they don't really have side effects
几乎没有副作用，
and you don't need to use them that
而且你不需要经常使用就能
benefit if you've seen my most recent
获益。如果你看过我最近
post on LinkedIn you probably have seen
在LinkedIn上的帖子，你可能已经注意到，
that I'm on a bit of a hiring spree at
我目前正在
the moment across my company flight
我的公司Flight
group trying to find the world's best
Group进行大规模招聘，努力寻找世界上最优秀的
talent and throughout these years of
人才。多年来，在
building these businesses my first Port
创建这些公司的过程中，我招聘的首选平台
of Call for hiring has always been
一直是
LinkedIn jobs who are a proud sponsor of
LinkedIn Jobs，他们也是本播客的赞助商。
reasons number one LinkedIn isn't just
原因有二。 第一，LinkedIn 不仅仅是
another job board it has a vast network
一个招聘网站，它拥有
of more than a billion professionals and
超过十亿专业人士和
quality candidates which I believe makes
优质候选人的庞大网络，我认为这使它成为
it the best place to find and hire
寻找和聘用其他任何地方都
professionals you can't find anywhere
找不到的专业人士的最佳平台。
else and number two their processing
第二，
features LinkedIn is constantly finding
LinkedIn 的招聘流程功能非常强大。LinkedIn 不断改进
ways to make the hiring process easier
招聘流程，提供
with super easy and intuitive features
超级简单直观的功能。
hiring is easy when you have that many
拥有如此多的
quality candidates in fact 86% of small
优质候选人，招聘就变得轻而易举。事实上，86% 的小型
businesses get a qualified candidate
企业都能
within 24 hours through Linkedin jobs
在 24 小时内通过 LinkedIn Jobs 找到合格的候选人。立即
AC to post your job for free right now
访问 linkedin.com 免费发布您的职位。
and of course terms and conditions
当然，条款和条件
apply when you think about biological
适用。说到生理
age if you are giving me some advice on
年龄，如果你要给我一些
lowering my biological age I'm 31 now
降低生理年龄的建议，我现在 31 岁。是的，
yeah you're 31 I'm 31 just a baby but
你 31 岁，我 31 岁，我还是个孩子，但
I'd like to be 25 biologically or 21
我希望生理年龄是 25 岁，或者 21 岁。
biologically yeah so I know you had
我知道你邀请了
Brian Johnson on the podcast he probably
Brian Johnson 上播客，他可能给了
G me some advice yeah he's got a eat
我一些建议。是的，他说要吃
breakfast and eating my 11 go to bed at
早餐，11 点吃完，晚上
8 uh no no when I speak yeah speak to J
8 点睡觉。呃，不，不，当我跟
Brian Johnson I have to buy some like
Brian Johnson 说话的时候…… 我得花
$5,000 Contraption and strap it to
五千美元买个什么玩意儿，早上绑在
myself in the morning and I just it's
自己身上，
lunch yeah yeah but the simple things
午饭就吃两根草，是啊是啊，但真正对
that have had the biggest impact on your
你的生理年龄影响最大的，是哪些简单的事情呢？
8020 on this yeah yeah yeah uh well I
这其中的8020是什么意思？嗯，我
wrote a book about it yeah you did
写了一本书，
called young forever yeah uh and it it's
叫《永远年轻》，是啊，其实
not that hard uh you know as we talked
没那么难。就像我们之前聊到的“
about the blue zones it's eat real food
蓝色地带”，要吃真正的食物。我
I would say eliminate Ultra processed
建议你戒掉超加工
food y dramatically reduce or limit
食品，大幅减少或限制饮食
sugar and starch from your diet flour
中的糖和淀粉，尤其是面粉
products
制品。一定要
particularly make sure you exercise so I
锻炼。所以我
think you know in terms of of and by the
觉得，就
way in terms of eating just to make a
饮食而言，还有
few more points give yourself 12 to 14
几点需要注意：睡前12到14个
hours overnight from eating first meal
小时，第一餐
should be protein and it should be 30 to
应该是蛋白质，30到
40 grams of protein that'll help you
40克蛋白质，这有助于你
build muscle which is the currency of
增肌，而肌肉是
longevity so if you want to live long
长寿的基石。所以，如果你想长寿、
and be strong and be able to do stuff
强壮，能够做各种事情，
and not you know have trouble getting up
而不是起床都困难，那就……
out of it chair or TI your shoelaces you
无论是椅子还是鞋带，你
need to build muscle and that protein is
需要增肌，而蛋白质
critical in the morning you need to have
至关重要。早上你需要摄入
a phytochemically rich diet which means
富含植物化学物质的饮食，这意味着
lots of colorful vegetables lots of good
大量的彩色蔬菜、大量的优质
fats and and the right kinds of protein
脂肪以及合适的蛋白质。这很
so that's that's pretty straightforward
简单明了。
again I've written lots of books I talk
我写过很多书，
about the diet in there but it's those
里面都谈到了饮食，但这些
are the sort of the main things in the
是“
Young Forever longevity diet you talk
永葆青春”长寿饮食法的主要内容。你提到的
about the the 75% of your plate should
餐盘中75%应该
be vegetables yeah this point about
是蔬菜。是的，关于将
limiting the protein to sort of 25% of
蛋白质限制在餐盘的25%左右这一点，
your plate is there a risk in having too
摄入过多肉类产品会有风险吗？
this is a interesting question you know
这是一个有趣的问题。
we looked at for example uh the Plains
例如，我们研究了上世纪初的平原
Indians like the Lakota at the turn of
印第安人，比如拉科塔人。
the last century 1900s they were the
他们是
longest live population on the planet
地球上最长寿的人群，寿命超过
they were 100 years old plus and all
100岁。他们
bison that was their diet pretty much
几乎只吃野牛，这就是他们的饮食，
and a few berries and maybe a few things
还有一些浆果，以及一些
they could dig up from the ground well
他们能从地里挖出来的东西。
they was bison pretty much yeah they
嗯，他们基本上只吃野牛。
they could eat the liver they'd eat the
他们会吃肝脏，会吃内脏，会
would eat the meat and they would have I
吃骨髓，会吃肉，我
think some some veggies from the berries
想他们还会吃一些蔬菜，比如浆果、
or roots or things that they would have
根茎之类的，
but it was very limited and they had
但种类非常有限，而且他们
lots of longevity um there there's I
寿命很长。嗯，我的
mean meat is a very nutrient food so I
意思是，肉类是一种营养非常丰富的食物，所以我
think the challenge with meat and this
认为肉类的挑战在于——这完全
is a whole another tangent that would
是另一个话题，
take us an hour to go through but you
我们得花一个小时才能讲完——你
know vegan or is not vegan meat not
知道，素食者吃肉，或者说非素食者吃肉，肉类是地球
nutritionally densest Foods on the
上营养最丰富的食物之一，
planet it's the best source of protein
是构建肌肉的最佳蛋白质来源，
and we should be eating regeneratively
我们应该吃再生
raised meat which is hard to find but
养殖的肉类，这很难找到，但像
there's places like force of nature
Force of Nature这样的网站
where you can get online you can get elk
可以在网上买到麋鹿、
bison benison and uh even beef and and
野牛、鹿肉，甚至牛肉，
um you can eat good quality fish
你还可以吃优质的鱼和牧场饲养的
chicken you know we need that kind of
鸡肉。你知道，我们需要这种
protein particularly as we age to build
蛋白质，尤其是在我们年纪渐长的时候，
muscle because we get something called
因为我们会出现一种叫做
anabolic resistance our bodies resist
合成代谢抵抗的现象，我们的身体会抵抗
building muscle and you need more
肌肉的合成，你需要更多的
protein and you need more exercise and
蛋白质，你需要更多的运动，
and and so you know the the amount of
等等。所以你知道……
meat depends on what you're doing and
肉类摄入量取决于你的运动量、
your size and your your your lifestyle
体型和生活方式。
so if you're very active and you want to
如果你非常活跃，想要
build muscle and you want to lift
增肌，想要举重，那么你
day that's that's more than people think
每天可能需要每磅体重0.5到1克蛋白质。这比人们想象的要多。
so the way we sort of say protein needs
我们通常所说的蛋白质需求量
is based on deficiency diseases so the
是基于蛋白质缺乏症的。
recommended dietary allowance is point 8
推荐膳食摄入量是
G per kilo I'm talking about double that
每公斤体重0.8克，我说的是这个量的两倍。0.8
now8 gr is the amount that you need to
克是
prevent a protein deficiency disease not
预防蛋白质缺乏症所需的量，而不是
how much you need for Optimal Health and
维持最佳健康和正常机能所需的量。
functioning so you need to be able to
你需要
have the right protein at the right time
适时摄入适量的蛋白质，同时
you also need fasts and times to not
也需要禁食一段时间，让
have protein so your body can heal and
身体进行修复和
repair but it's it's like golden nox
恢复。这就像黄金
phenomena you need both and so I would
法则一样，两者都不可或缺。所以，我
say depending on your activity level and
认为根据你的运动量和运动强度，
how much you're doing you need more but
你可能需要更多蛋白质。但
you know roughly about you know 30 gram
大致来说，
three times a day which is not that much
每天三次，每次30克左右，这并不算多。
you know I I just had a bag of bong
我刚才吃了一
which is a little bag of beef right it's
小袋牛肉。 就像
like beef yeah it's a South African like
牛肉一样，对，是南非的
beef jerky and I was like after I ate it
牛肉干。我吃完之后看了看
was like looked at the package I was
包装，
like oh it's only it's 32 grams so I had
心想：哦，才32克！我
32 grams of protein for lunch right
午饭只摄入了32克蛋白质，这也太难了吧！
that's so hard I could have a 30 or 40
我本来可以喝一杯30克或40
gram protein shake what I had this
克的蛋白奶昔，就像我今天
morning that's I'm already at like you
早上喝的那杯，那样我已经摄入了
know uh 70 grams so I think the the body
70克蛋白质了。所以我觉得身体
needs that protein so I think food is
需要这些蛋白质，食物真的很
really important and and I talk about
重要。我在书中谈到了
how to activate longevity switches with
如何通过
food and phytochemicals in the book the
食物和植物化学物质激活长寿开关。
resistance training is really key for
抗阻训练对
longevity so if if you if you want to do
长寿至关重要。如果你想做
cardio that's great and I think we need
有氧运动，那很好，我认为
to both but but strength training three
两者都需要。但是，
times a week minimum 20 minutes is the
每周至少三次，每次20分钟的力量训练才是
key to Health and Longevity it will keep
健康长寿的关键。它能保持
your muscle strong it'll prevent what we
肌肉强壮，预防我们
call sarcopenia which is muscle loss one
所说的肌少症，也就是肌肉流失。
of the biggest things that happens as
随着
you get older you lose muscle and that
年龄增长，肌肉流失是最常见的问题之一，会
leads to metabolic issues inflammation
导致代谢问题、炎症、
pre-diabetes you know just all kinds of
糖尿病前期等等。
Health consequences sugar oh yeah said
糖会带来各种各样的健康后果，哦，对，有人说要
get rid of the sugar okay what about
戒糖，好吧，那
artificial sugars like in dark sweet
人造甜味剂呢？比如黑糖？
yeah I mean there's so much you know
嗯，我的意思是，
debated about this I was actually
关于这方面有很多争论。
reading a couple of papers yesterday
昨天我读了几篇论文，
Stephen and I was because I was not
斯蒂芬，因为我当时在
working on and there were these two
做另一个研究，跟这个没关系。其中有两篇
papers that were basically discounting
论文基本上否定了
the fact that artificial sweeteners had
人造甜味剂
any bad impact on health and I was like
对健康有任何不良影响的说法。我觉得很
oh interesting because you know there's
有意思，因为
some biology around this and I and I and
这里面涉及到一些生物学知识。然后我
I said let me see who funded this study
就想，让我看看是谁资助了这项研究，结果
and it says this stud was entirely
发现这项研究完全是
funded by the American Beverage
由美国饮料
Association formerly known as the
协会（以前叫
American soda pop Association oh wow and
美国汽水协会）资助的。哇！
the other study was similar
另一项研究也类似，
study said funded by so and so who's
说是由某某资助的，而某某又受可口可乐公司资助，
funded by Coca colola and who works for
并且为
the international sweeteners
国际甜味剂
Association so follow the
协会工作。所以，追查
money you know is it better than
资金流向，你会发现它比
drinking soda yes is it better than
喝汽水好吗？是的。它比
drinking water no are there potentially
喝水好吗？不。它有可能带来
untour consequences I think so because
不良后果吗？我认为有，因为
of it's on the microbiome and other
它会影响肠道菌群
things so if you're asking what are the
等等。所以，如果你问我应该怎么
things to do for my biological age how I
做，我的答案是…… 生物年龄、我的
eat it's exercise it's it's community so
饮食、运动、社区，所以
I really focus on community friends
我真的很注重社区、朋友、
relationships love it's like medicine
人际关系和爱，爱就像良药一样，
love is medicine and also making sure
爱就是良药。同时，我也确保自己能
that I manage stress I meditate I mean I
管理好压力，我会冥想。我
like this app called newom which
喜欢一个叫Newom的app，它
basically is like a binaural beats and I
基本上就像双耳节拍，我
put it on it just takes you into a
打开它，它就能让你进入一种
altered brain wave state uh and uh you
改变的脑波状态。嗯，你
know having fun man have fun is okay
知道，享受生活，享受生活是可以的，
longevity enjoying life yeah it makes
长寿，享受
life worth living as well doesn't it I
生活，是的，它也让生命更有意义，不是吗？我
guess we talk about longevity a lot but
想我们经常谈论长寿，但
you have to I guess you have to like the
你必须，我想你必须喜欢
life you live exactly yeah it has be fun
你所过的生活，没错，它必须充满乐趣。
expose them expose them expose them yeah
接触它们，接触它们，接触它们，嗯，那
what is that I I mean tell yeah never
是什么？我是说，告诉，嗯，我
heard the word before so first time I
以前从没听过这个词，我第一次
heard it was researching you yeah so
听到它是在研究你的时候。是的，这是
it's it's a scientific term that you
一个科学术语，你
know like your genome right your
知道，就像你的基因组、
metabolome your microbiome your exposome
代谢组、微生物组、暴露组，
is the SU total of everything that
是
you've been exposed to in your life and
你一生中接触过的所有东西的总和，以及它们
how it's impacted your biology in this
此刻如何影响你的生物学。
about this though that I was
关于这一点，我特别感兴趣的是…… 我
particularly interested in was that this
感兴趣的是，这是否
includes what's happened to your
包括你
ancestors yeah yes well the epigenetics
祖先的经历？是的，表观遗传学确实很
is really fascinating but but the expose
迷人，但暴露组（
a minute but but the exposome is what
exposome）指的是
you eat it's exercise it's your thoughts
你吃的食物、运动、
your feelings your microbiome
思想、感受、微生物群、
environmental toxins
环境毒素，以及你的
uh everything your relationships all of
人际关系等等，所有这些都属于
that is your exposome right so all that
你的暴露组。所有这些都会
influences your expression of your genes
影响你基因的表达，
and it turns out the 90% of disease is
而且事实证明，90%的疾病都
related to the exposome not the genome
与暴露组有关，而不是基因组，
which is a good news because we have
这是个好消息，因为我们可以
control over that so how the things that
控制它。那么，
happen to us impact the expression of
发生在我们身上的事情
our genes exactly and how it affects our
究竟是如何影响我们基因的表达，又是如何影响我们的
biology right how it turns them on and
生物学的呢？它是如何开启和关闭基因的？开启
off and yeah turn on and off genes
和关闭基因会
regulates our hormones our brain
调节我们的激素、大脑
chemistry or microbiome everything right
化学物质、微生物群等等。
it's everything you're exposed to
你所接触到的一切都
determines the quality of your life and
决定了你的生活质量和
your health in terms of ancestral
健康状况。就祖先的
effects there's a phenomenon called
影响而言，有一种现象叫做
epigenetics which is how we measure
表观遗传学，我们用它来衡量
biological age which is the effect of
生物年龄，也就是
this uh think of it your genes as the
这种影响。你可以把你的基因想象成……
keys on a piano there's 88
钢琴有88个
keys and you can create any kind of
琴键，你可以用它们创作任何类型的
music from that think about that you can
音乐。想想看，你可以
create classical music rock music jazz
创作古典音乐、摇滚乐、爵士乐、
Rock rag time reggae whatever you want
拉格泰姆、雷鬼乐，任何你想听的音乐，
and it's just 88
而它只有88个
keys the epig genome is the piano player
琴键。表观基因组就像钢琴家，
that controls the songs of your life
掌控着你人生的乐章。
right and and and it is determined by
它由
your life experience and what you do and
你的生活经历、你的行为、
what you eat and what you how you think
你的饮食、你的思维方式
and your your uh stress level and your
、你的压力水平、你的
relationships and your gut microbiome
人际关系、你的肠道菌群等等所有因素共同决定，所有这些都
all everything is affecting this in real
在实时影响着它，
time and it's a dynamic process so we
这是一个动态的过程。我们
now know that using different
现在知道，通过不同的
interventions of lifestyle or diet or
生活方式、饮食或
various supplements that you can reverse
各种补充剂干预，你可以逆转
your biological age that you can turn
你的生物年龄，你可以拨
back the biological clock that you can
回生物钟，让
get biologically younger as you get
你在生理年龄
chronologically older and so it's really
增长的同时变得更年轻。这是一项非常令人
exciting research there's even there's
兴奋的研究。甚至有一位
even uh scientist from Japan who won a
来自日本的科学家获得了
Nobel Prize finding these transcription
诺贝尔奖，他发现了可以
factors that regulate our gene
调节基因表达的转录因子，这些转录因子
expression that can be inserted into us
可以插入我们的体内，
and reprogram our genes and our
重编程我们的基因和表观
epigenome to become younger in other
基因组，使我们变得更年轻。
words can create an original stem cell
换句话说，它可以创造出一种原始的干细胞，我们
what we call a plur potent stem cell so
称之为多能干细胞。 所以
it'll take back the all the way back to
它会一直追溯到
embryonic like Benjamin Button all the
胚胎时期，就像本杰明·巴顿一样。当然，
way back now you don't want to go all
你不想一直追溯到那么久远，
the way back CU you're you know but but
你知道，但是，
but we have these systems built in us
但是，我们体内有这些内置系统，
and so we we now can actually regulate
所以我们现在实际上可以
this through
通过表观
epigenetic uh Behavior changes that we
遗传学来调节它。行为改变我们
know work and there are drugs that do
知道是有效的，而且也有药物和
this too there are pyrochemical that do
化学方法可以做到这一点。
this so it's it's a new era of study do
所以这是一个新的研究时代。
you believe that we inherit the trauma
你相信我们会继承
of our ancestors I I don't think it's a
祖先的创伤吗？我不认为这是一种
belief Stephen um the data is really
信仰，斯蒂芬。嗯，数据非常
clear if you look at Holocaust survivors
清楚。如果你看看大屠杀幸存者，
their children have way more issues in
他们的孩子在
terms of psychological stress anxiety
心理压力和焦虑方面的问题要多得多。911事件
during 911 in New York City and those
期间，纽约市有很多孕妇，这些
Offspring Have reprogrammed genetics
后代的基因
based on the trauma that their mother
根据他们母亲
experienced during that time and those
在那段时间经历的创伤进行了重编程，这些是
can be measured different genes are
可以测量的。不同的基因
expressed different pathways are
表达，不同的通路
expressed that cause for example a
表达，例如，导致
higher level of anxiety a decreased
更高的焦虑水平，
ability to process the stress hormones
处理压力激素的能力下降，
and many other phenomena that happen
以及许多其他由表观
that are programmed epigenetically we
遗传学编程的现象。我们
know that if you take in animal studies
知道这一点。 如果你研究动物实验，
if you take a for example glyphosate
比如以草甘膦为例，
which is sprayed on 70% of all crops
这种除草剂被喷洒在70%的农作物上，
it's a weed killer Roundup we call it in
我们现在称之为“农达”。
this days and if you give it to let's
如果你给
say a grandmother
一只祖母
Mouse but not to the the daughter and
鼠喷洒这种除草剂，但不
not to the granddaughter or grand
给它的女儿、孙女或孙辈（
whatever kid of the I don't know what
我不知道该怎么
you call grandkid mice anyway that there
称呼这些孙辈），那么
will be changes three generations down
三代之后的后代都会受到影响，这是
caused by that toxin that that original
由于其
ancestor was exposed to that will cause
祖先接触到的毒素造成的。这会导致
increased cancer metabolic issues kidney
癌症、代谢问题、肾脏
issues a whole series of phenomena that
问题以及一系列由表观
are caused by epigenetic changes so you
遗传变化引起的现象。所以，你给
spray the grandmother and then she has
祖母鼠喷洒了除草剂，它生了
one generation of kids and then then the
一代后代，然后
next generation of kids are still
下一代后代仍然会
impacted by spraying the grandmother
受到祖母鼠喷洒除草剂的影响。
yeah so you might have heard of Lamark
你可能听说过拉马尔，
have you heard of Darwin Darwin okay you
你听说过达尔文吗？
heard of Darwin Darwin basically had the
达尔文基本上提出了
theory of evolution which is that
进化论，即
species evolve through natural selection
物种通过自然选择进化，
and they change slowly based on
它们会随着时间的推移，在环境压力的作用下缓慢地改变
change their genes Lamar basically said
基因。拉马尔则认为
you can change genes inherit things very
基因可以很快地改变，遗传也很快。
quickly and so they were kind of both
所以
right in a sense Lamar was more talking
从某种意义上说，他们的观点都对，只是拉马尔的观点更倾向于进化论。
about epigenetics and dman was talking
关于表观遗传学，而Dman
more about uh you know genetic Evolution
更多地谈论的是基因进化
and mutations over time which you know
和随时间推移发生的突变，你知道，
both are true both are true and knew
两者都对，两者都对，而且都了解
about genes but they were both observing
基因，但他们都在观察一些
phenomena that are explained by exactly
现象，而这些现象恰恰可以用
what I'm talking about what is the most
我所说的来解释。在
through your years of work as it relates
你多年的工作中，你发现的与
to longevity and health and all of that
长寿和健康相关的最重要的事情是什么？
that we haven't talked about we we we
我们还没谈到这些。我们
spend so much time um Being Human doings
花了太多时间做“人”该做的事，
and not being human
而不是做“人”。
beings and the thing that I observed in
我在“
the blue zones was there was a lot of
蓝色地带”观察到的一点是，
being going on there was a lot of just
那里有很多事情在发生，有很多事情只是在做自己，
being you know and and how important
你知道，
slowing down is to actually Savor the
放慢脚步去
things that really matter that make life
真正品味那些让生活
beautiful like we were we I was with
美好的事物是多么重要。就像我们当时，我和
this Italian ladies that were taking me
几位意大利女士一起，她们带着
around these tour guides and we were
导游，我们正开
driving down out of this little village
车驶出山边的一个小村庄，突然一辆
car stops in front of us and just like
车停在我们面前，就这么停了下来，然后挥手示意
stops and kind of stops us and waves and
我们下车。
says get out of the car like okay what's
好吧，怎么
going on so we got out of the car this
回事？于是我们下了车，那
old man he was relatively Young by
是一位相对年轻的老人。 按照
Sardinian standards he was 86
撒丁岛的标准，他
named Carmine and and he said come and
叫卡迈恩，86岁了。他说来，
we sat down on the side of the stone
我们就坐在路边的石墙上，
talked for two hours he talked about his
聊了两个小时。他讲了他的
life he asked me questions we were
生活，问了我一些问题，我们
talking about philosophy politics
聊了哲学、政治、
religion what it was like when he was
宗教，还有他
younger we we went to and then he took
年轻时的经历。然后他带
me on a tour of his farm and showed me
我参观了他的农场，给我看
his sheep and the olive trees and the
他的羊、橄榄树、
fig trees and the vegetables he was
无花果树和他
growing and and I couldn't keep up with
种的蔬菜。我根本跟不上
him he ran up the hill I was he was like
他，他跑上山坡，我心想他真是太
so fit and you know he tell me the story
健壮了。他给我讲述了
of his life and you know when was the
他的人生故事，你知道吗？
last time someone did that they might
上次有人这么做是什么时候？
give you the finger if you shot in front
要是在他们面前开枪，他们可能还会朝你竖中指呢。
of them you know like and we don't have
我们
this this sort of value system anymore
现在没有这种重视
that values you know deep uh
深厚
relationships and deep conversations and
关系、深入对话和
deep connection and that's beautiful
深度联结的价值观了。
what you're doing you're you're creating
你正在做的真好，你正在创造
a space for deep connections and you
一个可以建立深度联结的空间。你
know you've gotten to know me in this
知道，在
last two hours in ways that know most
过去的两个小时里，你以大多数
people don't because you've asked
人无法做到的方式了解了我，因为你问了我
questions and you spend time and you're
问题，你花时间和我交流。 你很
curious and I've been feeling safe to
好奇，我觉得可以放心地
share it with you and like you know I
跟你分享。你知道，我
public before and so it's it's really
以前很少在公开场合说这些，所以能说出这些话真的很
something beautiful that that can come
美好。
out of that and then I feel oh somebody
然后我感觉，哦，有人
sees me I'm seen I'm heard and that
看到了我，我被看到了，我被听到了，这是一种
that's a powerful medicine so being seen
强大的力量。被看见是一种
is a powerful medicine love is a
强大的力量，爱是一种
powerful medicine connection belonging
强大的力量，联结和归属感
is powerful medicine I wonder how the
也是一种强大的力量。我很好奇
lives we live now are really changing
我们现在的生活方式究竟是如何改变
our brains as well you know we talk
我们的大脑的。你知道，我们谈论
about ADD and ADHD and autism all these
多动症、注意力缺陷障碍、自闭症等等，
kinds of things but you know the pace at
但你知道，我的
which I live my life at I often think
生活节奏太快了，我经常觉得自己好像
like I think I'm developing a disease
得了什么病。是的，
yeah 100% 100% I me I I just got back
百分之百，百分之百。我刚从
from um from pagonia and you know I do a
帕戈尼亚回来，你知道，我有
lot of stuff I have multiple companies
很多事情要做，我有好几家公司，
businesses I have a clinic I have
有诊所，有
patients I constantly dealing with
病人，我每天都要处理
million things every day and uh you know
无数的事情。你知道，
I sometimes I I do I feel like some I
有时候，我觉得自己好像得了
have ADD and I was in there in pagonia
多动症。我当时在帕戈尼亚，一个
in the middle of nowhere there's no sell
荒郊野外，没有商店。
service there's no Wi-fi there's just
这里没有Wi-Fi，只有
mountains nature and me and my wife we
群山和自然风光，我和妻子徒步走了
hiked over 10 12 hours a day sometimes
十多英里。 每天工作12个小时，有时
more and I felt my nervous system
甚至更久，我感觉我的神经系统
completely changed and I realized I
完全改变了。我意识到我
don't have ADD I have
不是患有注意力缺陷障碍（ADD），而是患有
ND which is nature deficit disorder yeah
自然缺陷障碍（ND）。
you know and I felt everything calmed
你知道，我感觉一切都平静
down I felt everything kind of settle I
下来了，一切都安定下来了。我
saw my heart rate variability which is a
看到我的心率变异性（HVR）——一个
metric that we can measure that checks
可以测量
our stress response double I'm like oh
我们压力反应的指标——下降了。我当时想，
God you know like and I I don't think of
天哪，你知道吗？我并不认为
myself as stress but it's like it's just
自己压力很大，但这就像是
this phenomena from being in our society
我们这个社会的一种现象。我们需要有意识地
and it takes a will to stop and pause
停下来，暂停一下，
and breathe and to go slower and to you
深呼吸，放慢脚步，去欣赏生活的
know smell the roses it's a cliche but
美好。虽然这听起来很老套，但
it's really it's a thing my friend one
确实如此。
of my best friends called Dom he we used
我最好的朋友之一叫Dom，我们以前经常
to roast him a little bit because his
取笑他，因为他的
heart rate variability was very very low
心率变异性非常非常低。我们连续
couple of weeks on end couple of months
几个星期，甚至几个月都在取笑他，
really cuz we we all have this like
因为我们每个人都有自己的
heart rate variability League table and
心率变异性排行榜。
and then he went on his honeymoon from
然后他去
month to Australia yeah and his heart
澳大利亚度蜜月，他的
rate variability went from like
心率变异性从20左右飙升到了
something like 20 or 30 to 140 wow and
20左右。 或者说，心率从30到140，哇！而这
all that was happening was he was
一切的发生，
basically just spending his time in
基本上就是他把时间都花在了
nature in the sunshine as well which is
阳光下的大自然里，这确实是
an important factor yeah and now and
一个重要的因素。是的，
since then he's managed to maintain his
从那以后，他主要通过待在大自然里来维持他的
heart rate variability predominantly by
心率变异性。
staying out in nature and I thought God
我想，天哪，这
that's so interesting yeah that it like
太有趣了。是的，它以如此
profound way it does you um before the
深刻的方式调节着我们的免疫系统。嗯，在
conversation started we were talking
谈话开始之前，我们
very excitedly about your new company
非常兴奋地聊起了你的新公司，
called function yeah sounds incredibly
叫做Function。是的，听起来对那些对Function感到
exciting for someone that's curious
好奇的人来说非常令人兴奋。Function是
about function what is it and and where
什么？在哪里
can they find it so you know most of us
可以找到它？你知道，我们大多数人
don't have access to what's happening
无法了解
under our skin right uh we have to go to
自己皮肤下的情况，对吧？我们必须去看
the doctor we have to get an appointment
医生，必须预约，必须
we have to hope they order the right
希望他们开对了
test we have to hope that they know how
检查，必须希望他们知道如何
to interpret the important tests we Hope
解读重要的检查结果，希望
they've kept up with the science we hope
他们跟上了科学的步伐，希望
they are you know doing all the right
他们正在做所有正确的
things but the truth is they're not and
事情，但事实并非如此。
unfortunately delayed in its adoption of
不幸的是，医学在采用
new science and so function is really an
新科学方面总是滞后。所以Function实际上是在
attempt to help you get access to your
尝试帮助你了解自己的身体状况。
own biology to be the CEO of your own
生物学让你成为自己
health to create a health database of
健康的CEO，建立一个包含所有自身数据的健康数据库。
eventually right now it's your blood
目前，它涵盖的是你的血液
test but eventually your biosensor data
检测结果，但最终会包括你的生物传感器数据、
your whole genomics all your medical
你的全基因组数据、所有医疗
records Imaging data your metabolome
记录、影像数据、你的代谢组、
your
你的
microbiome and and interpret all that in
微生物组等等。我们将所有这些数据进行解读，
a way that helps you get a personalized
帮助你实时了解自身
with your biology and then through
生物学的个性化状况。然后，通过
evidence-based science and through the
循证科学、
influence of expert opinion that also
专家意见（这同样
has value and through the wisdom that
具有价值）以及
comes from the patterns in your own data
从自身数据模式中汲取的智慧，我们可以为你
being able to create a personalized road
制定一份个性化的
map for your health over time and it's
健康路线图。这
not a one-time test it's it's it's being
并非一次性检测，而是
a member of function allows you twice
功能性检测的会员服务。
your testing for like
只需
$499 you get over 110 biomarkers you
499美元，你就能获得双倍的检测次数，检测超过110种生物标志物，并可以长期
track them over time you see the changes
追踪它们的变化。
checkup right we're doing for example
正如斯蒂芬所指出的，我们正在进行一些常规体检之外的检测。例如，
for cholesterol we're doing lipoprotein
对于胆固醇，我们进行脂蛋白
fractionation which looks at the
分级分离，检测
particle number and size it's less than
脂蛋白颗粒的数量和大小。 在
1% of all cholesterol tests it was
所有胆固醇检测中，有1%的人检测结果不准确。这项技术
discovered 40 years ago but 99% of
40年前就被发现了，但99%的
people don't get it right and it tells
人检测结果不准。结果显示，
us that 95% have problems with that 89%
95%的人存在胆固醇问题，89%的人胆固醇
have small particles which shows poor
颗粒较小，这表明
metabolic Health we're seeing 46% of
代谢健康状况不佳。我们发现46%的
people have inflammation with a high C
人存在炎症，C
reactor protein we're seeing 133% have
反应蛋白水平升高；133%的人患有
undetected we're finding cancers that
未被发现的自身免疫性甲状腺疾病；我们发现了一些之前
nobody found through liquid biopsies
通过液体活检无法发现的癌症；
we're finding that 67% have nutritional
我们发现67%的人存在营养
deficiencies and this is a very health
缺乏。这是一个非常健康的
population because we're still in beta
群体，因为我们的技术仍处于测试阶段，
and we're seeing they didn't even know
而且我们发现他们甚至不知道
we're affecting their health so I had so
我们的技术正在影响他们的健康。
lead athlete for example who's great but
例如，我曾遇到一位非常优秀的运动员，但
he had low iron and he had low vitamin D
他缺铁、缺维生素D
and he had low B vitamin and it was
和缺B族维生素，这
affecting his performance so it was like
影响了他的运动表现，就像
he had a disease so we're able to map
他患有某种疾病一样。因此，我们能够
this for people and provide a basically
为人们绘制出这些健康图谱，并根据学习结果提供一个类似
AI co-pilot for your health based on the
人工智能的健康助手。
learnings and you know AI is a scary
你知道，人工智能对人们来说是一个令人恐惧的
thing for people but the the truth is
东西，但事实是，在
that in medicine it's the best use case
医学领域，它…… 最佳应用场景：
would you rather have a dermatologist
您是希望一位
who's seen a few thousand lesions look
见过几千个病变的皮肤科医生检查
at your skin and see if it's a cancer or
您的皮肤，判断是否是癌症，
not or an AI that sees billions of
还是希望人工智能能够识别数十亿个
lesions and can actually know what's
病变，并真正了解您的皮肤状况？
really going on so we're going to be
我们将以
able to do this in a very safe way for
非常安全的方式为您提供这项服务，让您拥有自己的
you to to you own your data and you can
数据，您可以
personalize your approach you can
个性化您的治疗方案，您可以
upgrade your biological Health you can
提升您的生物健康，您可以
do that biological upgrade that I talked
进行我之前提到的生物升级，
about and and you can share the data
您可以
with your doctors and it's going to I
与您的医生共享数据。我
think transform medicine uh and right
认为这将彻底改变医学。
now you know we've just started uh in
目前，我们刚刚开始测试，
betab but we have almost 30,000 members
但我们已经拥有近 3 万名会员，
we've had seen over three million data
收集了超过 300 万个
points of people's biology um we have
生物学数据点。
this available now at function
现在，您可以在 functionhealth.com 上找到这项服务。
health.com if you go to function
访问 functionhealth.com，
health.com Mark you can learn more about
了解更多信息，
it and you can get off the weight list
您可以从体重列表中移除，
and get to see CU we have 100,000 people
并查看 CU（我们目前有 10 万人
on the weight list and get to learn
在体重列表中），了解
about your own biology and what people
您自身的生物学状况以及人们
are discovering is really life-changing
正在发现的内容。
for them I'm very excited for you and
对他们来说，这将改变人生。我为你感到非常兴奋，
it's so wonderful to see how AI is
看到人工智能
creating new opportunities within health
在健康
and and wellness that weren't previously
和保健领域创造以前从未
available so it's you know it's all been
有过的新机遇，真是太棒了。你知道，这一切都
happening over the last sort of 12
发生在过去12个
months in the world of AI and from I
月左右的人工智能领域，我
hope some incredible solutions emerg
希望一些令人难以置信的解决方案能够涌现，
that bring down the cost and access the
降低医疗保健的成本和可及性。关键是，
the thing is so affordable for most
对大多数
people it's like less than you spend on
人来说，医疗保健的成本非常低，就像你
a cup of coffee every day it's like $130
每天花在一杯咖啡上的钱一样少，每天大约130美元左右。
something a day you know and for most
你知道，对大多数
people you know that that's affordable
人来说，这是可以负担的，当然
some people not but when you think about
有些人负担不起。但是，想想你
the what's your wealth your health is
的财富是什么？你的健康就是
your wealth like I said earlier in the
你的财富。就像我之前在
podcast a healthy man wants many things
播客里说的，一个健康的人想要很多东西，
a sick man wants one thing I think it's
一个病人想要的只有一样东西。我想这是
a Chinese proverb
一句中国谚语，对吧？
right you have an incredible podcast
你有一个很棒的播客节目
called The Doctor's Pharmacy which is
叫《医生的药房》，这是最
one of the top health podcasts where you
热门的健康播客之一，你在节目中
discuss the sort of intersection between
讨论了
health food and and policy which I
健康食品和政策之间的交集，我
recommend everyone to go and check
推荐大家去
account you've written a lot of books A
听听。你还写了很多书，很多都是
Lot 19 too many I'm done for a minute
19本。 我先说到这里，
I'm going to I'm going to recommend one
我打算推荐一本书，
and then I'll let you recommend another
然后再让你推荐另一本。对，对，
recommend if you have to recommend one I
如果你必须推荐一本，你会推荐哪一本呢？《
Young Forever is my latest book and it's
永葆青春》是我最新的一本书，
where I poured my entire knowledge base
我把所有关于如何优化健康的知识、
and tips and ideas and strategies about
技巧、想法和策略都倾注其中。
how to optimize your health and it's not
它不仅适用于
just for longevity for any area of
延年益寿，也适用于
Health that you have issues with it's
你健康方面的任何问题，非常
powerful I was going to recommend that
有效。我本来也想推荐这
one as well but I'm going to say food
本书，但我还是想推荐《食物
fix um because that book is fantastic
修复》，因为这本书太棒了，
and that's one of the ones um the book
而且它是
longevity That You released recently
你最近出版的关于长寿的书之一。《
Young Forever is fantastic book but the
永葆青春》确实很棒，但《
food fix book as well is really
食物修复》这本书也对
clarifying for a lot of people that are
很多
probably confused about food um we have
可能对食物感到困惑的人来说非常清晰明了。我们
a closing tradition on this podcast
这个播客有个结尾的传统，上
where the last guest leaves a question
一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，而他们
for the next not knowing who they're
并不知道这个问题会留给谁。留给
been left for you is interesting because
你的问题很有意思，因为
it's a little bit similar to what I
它和我
asked you earlier but with a slight
之前问你的问题有点类似，但略有
variation what is the most interesting
不同。
and revealing question Steve should have
史蒂夫应该问你的最有趣、最有启发性的问题是什么？ 哦，对了，
asked you but didn't oh and this is for
这是给
the next guest no this was left for you
下一位嘉宾的。不，这是留给你的，
and they didn't know who they were
他们也不知道要
leaving it for oh I see okay
留给谁。哦，我明白了。好的。嗯，
um I would say you know who were the
我想说，你知道谁对
biggest influences in my life living or
我的影响最大吗？无论在世与否。
dead so Mark who are the biggest
马克，
influences you're gonna have to answer
你
now people are Wonder all right uh so I
现在得回答这个问题了，大家都很想知道答案。好的。嗯，我
would say living is a gentleman who's an
想说，在世的是一位
unsung hero uh a man named Jeffrey Bland
默默无闻的英雄，名叫杰弗里·布兰德，他
who's a nutritional biochemist studied
是一位营养生物化学家，曾师从
with lonus Pauling who won two priz is
洛纳斯·鲍林，鲍林获得了两项大奖，他可以说是
science in in the modern way who uh
现代营养科学之父，
really established this field of
真正奠定了
functional medicine and he he's a
功能医学这一领域。他是一位
nutritional biochemist but
营养生物化学家，但
he he's a genius he he's he's a
他也是一位天才，一位
synthesizer so every time I would see
综合分析家。几十年来，我每次见到
him for decades he would have a pile of
他，他都会带着一摞厚厚的
scientific papers this thick like you
科学论文，你
know a foot thick carrying with him all
知道，大概有一英尺厚吧。
the time and he would Hoover those
他会把这些资料仔细研究，进行
things up and he synthesizes it and he's
综合分析，几
seen patterns in that data for decades
十年来，他一直在这些数据中发现一些模式，这些模式早于
we're seeing now in me medicine so most
我们现在看到的这场革命。 现在，就我医学而言，
things I talked about today he he
我今天谈到的大部分内容，他
basically understood by seeing the
基本上都是通过观察各个
intersections across Specialties so he's
专科的交叉点来理解的。他是一位
sort of a polymath in science and he
博学多才的科学家，他对
influenced my work he saved my life
我的工作产生了影响。就我
personally by learning about this model
个人而言，通过学习这个模型，我
I I was able to save my health he's
得以保住健康，他也
helped me help millions of people so
帮助我帮助了数百万人，所以
he's a huge influence uh the other I
他对我的影响非常巨大。我
think main influence on my life was
认为对我人生影响最大的另一个人是
Henry thorough who was a
亨利·托雷，他是一位
transcendentalist lived in the 1800s
生活在19世纪的超验主义者，
wrote a book called Walden I if you've
写了一本书叫《瓦尔登湖》。如果你
heard about it but it's a profound book
听说过这本书，那真是一本意义深远的书。这本书讲述的是一个名叫瓦尔登（Walden）的
uh it was basically a guy who Walden
人，他
Pond and lived there by himself in a
独自一人住在波士顿郊外的瓦尔登湖畔的一间小
cabin with nothing almost and wrote
屋里，几乎一无所有，并在那里生活。这是一本经典之作，
about wrote about it and he had you this
他用一种
beautiful way of writing and describing
优美的文笔描述了
nature and life and philosophy and it
自然、生活和哲学，其中还
really also included a lot of Eastern
融入了许多东方
philosophy embedded in it which I didn't
哲学思想，而我当时并没有
realize at the time and so that book uh
意识到这一点。 那本书
really impacted my childhood
真的对我的童年产生了
profoundly Dr Mark hman thank you so
深远的影响。马克·赫曼博士，非常感谢您
much for taking the time today and thank
今天抽出时间，感谢
you for all of your wisdom and honesty
您所有的智慧、诚实
and openness it's incredibly important
和坦率，这非常重要。
and uh the work you've done over the
您在
last couple of decades has changed lives
过去二十年里所做的工作改变了许多人的生活，
save lives and in more so than I think
拯救了许多人的生命，其影响之大，恐怕
you'd probably ever realize and more so
您自己都难以想象，也远远超出了
than we could ever count so thank you
我们所能统计的范围。非常感谢您一直以来所从事的
for that incredibly Noble and worthy
这项崇高而有价值的事业，以及您未来将要
going to come with that so I wish you
从事的各项工作，包括相关的功能性工作等等。祝您一切顺利！非常
the very very BL thank you so much for
感谢您抽出
time how do you guys manage your stress
时间。你们是如何应对压力的呢？
this month is Stress Awareness Month and
这个月是压力意识月，
it's a topic that I'm super passionate
我对此非常热衷，
about and we talk about a lot on this
我们在播客中也经常讨论这个话题。
podcast I personally manage my stress by
我个人是通过
prioritizing my health and well-being
优先考虑自己的健康和幸福来应对压力的。
going to the gym is my number one form
去健身房是我最重要的
of therapy and I couldn't be without
疗愈方式，
those two things as you guys know whoop
这两件事对我来说至关重要。正如你们所知，Whoop
is a sponsor of this podcast and I'm an
是本播客的赞助商，我也是这家
investor in the company as well for
公司的投资者。可能有些人
those of you that don't know we've
还不知道。 我们
actually created a stress monitor within
在这个设备里内置了一个压力监测器，
this device not only does this help me
它不仅能帮助我
real time throughout the day but it also
实时识别一天中压力较大的时段，还能为
provides me with the tools I need to
我提供
deal with stresses as they come up
应对压力的工具。
throughout the day and it's based on
这个监测器基于
scientifically backed breathing
科学的呼吸
exercises and research that's been
练习和
developed by Leading neuroscientists
顶尖神经科学家的研究成果。
gamechanging for me and I highly
对我来说，这项功能彻底改变了我的生活。
recommend if you're someone that's
如果你也
looking to manage your stress levels
想控制压力，我强烈推荐你
then head over to join whoop.com
加入 whoop.com
CEO where we'll give you 30 days
CEO，我们将提供 30 天
risk-free and zero commitment to try
无风险、零承诺的
whoop let me know how you get
whoop 试用期。请告诉我你是如何获得
[Music]
[音乐] 的。